hello everyone today we'll talk about
the problem of finding longest common
subsequence first let's define what is
longest common subsequence we have two
strings x and y and we want to find
their longest common subsequence first
let's find the common subsequence of
length one which is easy X has a y has a
so a is a common subsequence of x and y
and so is C and so is G and then let's
find the common subsequence of length 2
x has a see Y has a and C note that the
common subsequence doesn't have to be
consecutive
exhale CC one hell CC exhale see G will
have C and G X has a G one has a G next
let's find the common subsequence of
length three X has a CC y doesn't have a
CC x has C c/g
Y also has CC G so the common
subsequence of length 3 is C c/g next
finding the common subsequence of length
4 for X it must be a C c/g
and there is no AC C G in Y so there is
no common subsequence of length 4
so by manually analyzing these two
string we can find that the longest
common subsequence of these two string
is CCG with the length of three this
problem of finding longest common
subsequence is a very practical problem
for example we know a DNA sequence can
be expressed as a stream of characters
ACGT so by finding the longest common
subsequence of two strands of DNA we can
see how similar these two strands of DNA
are therefore tell if the two persons
are related or not it can help people to
find their long-lost child for example
but the problem is we have to look at
very long sequences of DNA strings now
we have much longer X&Y and it is no
longer possible to manually find the
longest common subsequence of x and y we
have to write a program and implement
some algorithm to find out the answer
let's denote the size of X is n under
the size of Y is M since X is shorter
than Y so our algorithm is like this for
integer I from n to 1 find all
subsequence of X with length of I find
all the subsequence of Y with the length
of I if there is a common subsequence
between x and y we've found the answer
break
so this algorithm is simple and
straightforward we know it will work the
problem is how complex is the cell
result let's consider how many
subsequence does X have with the lens of
I the answer is this so the worst case
complexity of this for loop is a
summation of this formula for every I so
this is the complexity of the algorithm
and I just you that you have learned
from your math class this is exponential
in n so this algorithm is very complex
and we cannot afford it we have to find
a better algorithm now let's try to use
dynamic programming to solve this
problem the idea of dynamic programming
is to solve a complex problem by
breaking it down into smaller subproblem
so here since the problem with size of N
and M is too complex for us let's
consider a problem with smaller size I
and J I is less than N and J is less
than M
so let's define C IJ is the length of
longest common subsequence of sequence X
1 to X I which is this 1 and y 1 to y J
which is this one note that our index
start with 1 and by definition CI 0 is
equal to 0 for all I because 0 means the
length of the sequence is 0 so it's
Long's the common subsequence must be 0
and for the same reason C 0 J is also
equal to 0 for all J and our goal is to
gradually increase I and J and
eventually find C and M to achieve this
goal the key question is how to use C
with smaller I and J to computer C with
greater I and J by analyzing the problem
we come up with this formula if X I
equal to XJ which means the last item is
the same then C IJ equal to C I minus 1
J minus 1 plus 1 since the last item is
the same so if we take off the last item
then we get CI minus 1 and J minus 1
otherwise if the last item is not the
same then CIJ equal to the bigger of C I
minus one J and the C I J minus 1 since
we have the initial condition and we
have this formula to derive C with
bigger I and J eventually we'll find CNM
now let's look at our code in the main
function I create two string x and y and
then I call the function calc LCS this
is the function that will implement our
algorithm so let's finish up this
function the first step is to create C
and initialize it so I have created a
matrix C which is to store the length of
longest common subsequence of sequence X
1 to X I and y 1 to y J note that our
index start from 1 so the first item of
each string is ignored and then I
initialize C to be n by M matrix and
each entry of the matrix is initialized
to 0 so we also have finished the
initialization of C value for C 0 and C
0 J the next step is to implement this
formula
so we have two nested loops the outer
loop is for I and that inner loop is for
J if X I equal to YJ then CIJ is equal
to C I minus 1 J minus 1 plus 1
otherwise CIJ will take the bigger of C
I J minus 1 and C I minus 1 J so this is
exactly the replica of this formula so
by the end of these two loops C will
contains the longest common subsequence
length of x and y so let's print out the
C and inspect its value this is a
utility to print matrix that I created
and now we can actually run the program
so this is the C and the CNM in this guy
which indicates the length of the
longest common subsequence is 5 so we
have found the length of the longest
common subsequence but we don't know
what the sequence is yet in order to
find out the sequence we need more
information to be specific we need a
data structure to save the position of
the elements of the longest common
subsequence so let's create another
matrix called s and s is to store the
position of longest common subsequence
and let's use a matrix of char to save
the position and we need to initialize
the size of s to be n by M
and if X I equal to YJ will set s IJ
equal to s s means they are the same and
when they are the same it means either X
I or Y J doesn't matter which one
because they are the same either X I or
Y J is one item of the longest common
subsequence if they are not the same and
if C IJ minus one is bigger than say I
minus one J then we set s IJ equal to J
what this means is even if we take away
the last item of Y we can still find the
same longest common subsequence so we
can safely take away the last item of Y
otherwise we'll set s IJ equal to AI
which means we can safely take away the
last item of X and still can find the
same longest common subsequence so s has
saved all the information we need to
find the longest common subsequence so
finally we can write a function to print
out the longest common subsequence let's
call our function print L say s and it
will take s as one parameter X as
another parameter and X dot size minus 1
that is our n why does size minus 1 that
is our M
and our function would be look like this
if I equal to zero or J equal to zero it
means we have reached it at the end
there will not be any common subsequence
left if si J equal to s it means X I and
Y J are the same so X I must be one
element of the long straumann
subsequence so we just print it out if s
IJ equal to J it means we can safely
take away the last element of Y and they
can still find the same longest common
subsequence LS s IJ must be equal to I
which means we can safely take away the
last element of X and can still find the
longest common subsequence so let's run
the program
it prints out a GGA see that's the
longest subsequence let's see
AC AGG AC AGG AC yes that appears to be
the longest common subsequence that's
all for today feel free to subscribe to
my channel and check out the other
videos I have bye bye