hello everyone today we will talk about
the problem of finding the longest
increasing subsequence first let's
define what is increasing subsequence
for example we have a vector like this
what increasing subsequence does it have
it has three six three six is increasing
and it is a subsequence of this vector
two six also increasing and it is a
subsequence two four five two four five
and one even though it only has one
element we can still consider it as a
increasing sequence and that the longest
increasing subsequence is the longest
among all the increasing subsequence so
our problem is for a vector d of size n
find its longest increasing subsequence
on the surface this is not a difficult
problem as long as we find all the
subsequence of D and extract those
subsequence who is increasing and then
we can find that the longest increasing
subsequence
so our first algorithm is like this for
integer I from n to one find all the
subsequence of D with the length of I if
there is one increasing subsequence then
we are done that one ought to be the
longest increasing subsequence so we can
break
this algorithm is simple and it should
work but the problem is how complex is
this let's consider how many subsequence
does d have with the length of I the
answer is this formula so the worst case
complexity of this for loop is a
summation of this formula with all I so
we get this for I equal to n - 1 and sum
up every value of this formula and I
just you have learned from your math
class this is exponential in n so the
complexity of this algorithm is not
acceptable we have to find a better
algorithm now let's try to solve the
same problem with dynamic programming
the idea of dynamic programming is to
solve a complex problem by breaking it
down into smaller subproblems
so first let's find it a smaller
subproblem let's define a vector L and L
I itself is also a vector which is the
longest increasing subsequence of D that
ends with di in other words of all the
increasing subsequence of D that ends
with di Li is the longest and by
definition L 0 is d 0 because the
increasing subsequence that ends with d
0 must be D 0 itself
let's use our old example to find the
ll0 must be 3 L 1 is 2 because 3 is
bigger than 2 so 3 2 is not increasing L
2 is 2 6 our 3 is 2 4 l 4 is 2 4 5 and
our 5 is 1 because 1 is the smallest so
this is our definition of L a smaller
sub-problem and as long as we find every
vector of L we can easily find the
longest increasing subsequence in this
case 2 4 5 so we have an initial
condition and if we can find a dual
evasion formula which can use L with
smaller I to computer L with bigger I
and then we can find every L by
analyzing the problem we get this
formula our eye is looking at every l j
where j is less than i and DJ which is
the tale of l j is less than di and then
pick the one that is the longest and
append the i to the end of it let's look
at our example let's say our I is for so
L I is L for and di is 5 and we have
already found every L from L 0 to L 3
and next we want to find L 4
so first we look at every L from l0 to
l3 whose tail is less than di 5 so we
got l0 l1 and l3 whose tail is less than
5 and then we pick the longest which is
l3 and lastly we append di to the end of
it so we got 2 4 5 so this is the
algorithm if it is still not clear to
you I'm sure it will be more clear when
you look at the code this is the C++
implementation of the algorithm in the
main function I create a vector of int
and then pass the vector to a function
called calculus which calculate the
longest increasing subsequence so this
function calculus is where the algorithm
is implemented as you see the code is
quite compact it only has about 10 lines
of code first we create L and L is the
same size as the input data D and then
we initialize l0 to be D 0 that is the
initial condition we have talked about
about L and then we start the loop to
find every entry of L since we already
have l0 so our group will start with 1 I
will start with 1
and for each I will have a inner loop of
J and J is from zero to I minus one and
for all the J's we'll find the longest
LJ whose tail DJ is less than di and
here we are using Li as a temporary
variable to store the longest LJ so by
end of the inner loop Li is equal to the
longest LJ whose tail is less than di
and lastly we append di to the end of Li
it is this di that we are talking about
by end of all the loops we have computed
every entry of L to visualize the lose
out let's print out every entry of L
this is a printed here that I have to
print a vector now we can run the
program
so it print out every entry of L this is
l0 l1 l2 l3 l4 l5 and l4 is the longest
increasing subsequence so this result is
the same as the result that we have
manually calculated lastly let's analyze
the complexity of our algorithm this is
n and this is another n so the
complexity of our algorithm is n square
which is much better than exponential in
n so the idea of dynamic programming is
sacrificing some of the space to
substantially reduce the time complexity
in this case we have sacrificed the
space of L to bring the time complexity
from exponential in n to n square that's
all for today feel free to subscribe to
my channel and check out the other
videos I have bye-bye