hello everyone today we will find
minimum spanning tree with classical air
exam classical algorithm is implemented
with disjoint sets so my previous video
on disjoint sets is a prerequisite for
this video in previous video we have
talked about disjoint set and how it
operates but we haven't talked about how
this joint sets can be useful today
we'll use disjoint set to find the
minimum spanning tree of a graph what is
minimum spanning tree so this is the
graph that we have it has a bunch of
vertices and a bunch of edges each edge
has a weight the minimum spanning tree
is a subset of edges that connects all
the vertices in the graph and it has
minimum total weight so in this case the
minimum spanning tree is CF AF and a B
because they connect all the vertices in
the graph and they have the minimum
total weight so the problem we want to
solve is given a graph with weighted
edges find its minimum spanning tree
today we'll use classical algorithm to
find the minimum spanning tree and
classical algorithm utilizes disjoint
sets
you call that disjoint sets has two
operations find and Union find we'll
take an item and then return the
disjoint set that item belongs to and
the Union will merge the two disjoint
sets of these two items into one
disjoint set so now let's talk about the
classical algorithm
we define a a is used to store all the
edges of the minimum spanning tree so
initially a is empty and eventually
we'll return a then for each vertex of
the graph make a disjoint set with that
vertex so each vertex will be used to
create like single vertex disjoint set
and then sort all the edges by weight
increasingly so the edge with smallest
weight will be in the front and the
edges with biggest weight will be in the
end and then for each edge that connects
v1 and v2 the smallest edge will be
taken first
if the disjoint set of v1 is not the
same as the disjoint set of v2 then we
push that edge into a and then merge the
disjoint sets of v1 and v2 into one
disjoint set now let's use this example
of graph to walk through the algorithm
first we take the edge with smallest
weight which is CF and it's in C and F
do not belong to the same disjoint set
so we go ahead and merge them and push
the edge into a and next one is AF which
has the weight of two and again a and F
do not belong to the same disjoint set
so merge them and push them into a
next is de de do not belong to the same
disjoint set merge and push to the a
next one is CD note that CFA belong to
the same disjoint set and de belong to
the same disjoint is set so C and D do
not belong to the same set
so again merge them and push to a next
one is f e now a F CDE all belong to the
same set so f e belong to the same set
so we should not push this edge into a
next one is a B and a B do not belong to
the same set so merge and push now we
have a spanning tree that connects all
the vertices and we believe this
spanning tree has the minimum total
weight now let's look at our code our
graph is represented with a vector of
vertices and a vector of edges an edge
is modeled with two vertices that the
edge connects and a weight in the main
function I create a graph and its
vertices contains ABCDE F and it has all
the edges that connects the vertices
essentially I'm creating a graph like
this
and then I call the function classical
with the graph as its parameter this
will use classical algorithm to find the
minimum spanning tree this is the data
structure of disjoint set we use parent
to record the parental relationship
between the vertices and they use the
rank to record the depth of the tree
remember the purpose of the rank is to
flatten the tree so that we have better
performance of the find function the
find function and a union function are
the same function that we talked about
last time we have added another function
called mix set which will take one
vertex and make a single vertex disjoint
set and initialize its rank to zero this
is the classical function that
implements classical algorithm first we
create a a a is a vector of edge and a
will be used to store all the edges of
the minimum spanky and then we take each
vertex of the graph and make it a single
vertex disjoint a set and then sort all
the edges according to their weight and
then take each edge find that the loot
of its first vertex find out the loot of
its second vertex and if root one and
the loot two are not the same loot we
push the edge into a and then call Union
root one and loot two this will merge
the disjoint set of vertex one and
vertex two into one disjoint set
so by the end of this loop we'll find
the minimum spanning tree of the graph
let's print out the minimum spanning
tree and run the program
so this is the minimum spanning tree
computed by our classical function and
it's the same result as what we have
manually computed now let's consider
what's the complexity of this algorithm
the sorting will take the complexity of
e timings of log E and this is e and
since we have used the link to flatten
the tree we can assume both find and
Union to be very fast so the performance
of this algorithm is dominated by the
sort algorithm that's all for today feel
free to subscribe to my channel and
check out the other videos I have
bye-bye