hello everyone today we will talk about
another algorithm to find the minimum
spanning tree it's called Premal prism
and again we use a to store all the
edges of the minimum spanning tree so
initially a is empty and eventually will
return a and then for each vertex in the
graph we give it two attributes a key
and a parent each key is initialized to
infinity and each parent is initialized
to a now so this is the initial
condition for all the vertices and then
we randomly choose a looot and set the
key of that loot to be 0 so we pick a as
the loot and the set a ski value to be 0
then we create a queue which contains
all the vertices in the graph next we
enter the while loop we find the vertex
in queue with the smallest key in this
case the vertex in cure with smallest
key is a because a is key is 0 then a
way we move a from Q since the parent of
a is now so we'll skip this statement
then we'll update the attributes for all
the vertices who is adjacent to a let's
start with F if the weight of the edge
is less than the key of F we'll update
f ski to be this weight and F parent to
be a
same thing for B since the weight of the
edge is less than the key of B we'll
update these key to be the weight and
the B's parent to be a now enter the
second loop a has been removed from Q so
now Q contains all the vertices in
purple the vertex in Q with the smallest
key is F since f ski is 2 and the parent
of F is not now so we need to execute
this statement we'll push the edge
between F and F parent in this case this
edge into a so this is one of the edge
in minimum spanning tree and then we
update all the vertices that's adjacent
to F as well as their key is less than
the weight of the edge we'll update
these vertices so in this case all three
will be updated and now a contains the
edge of AF and both a and F has been
removed from Q now enter the third loop
the vertex in Q with the smallest key is
C so we'll remove C from Q and added the
edge of C F into the minimum spanning
tree and then update the attributes of
C's neighbors since this weight is less
than these key D will be updated but
this edge is bigger than B's key so B
will not be updated so we only need to
update D now a contains a F and C F and
a CF are all removed from Q the fourth
loop the vertex in cure with smallest
key is either B or D let's choose B and
will you remove B from Q and add B F
into a since P doesn't have a neighbor
that belongs to Q so there's no neighbor
need to be updated and the next one with
the smallest key is D so a add a CD into
a and last one is e we add te into a so
eventually queue is empty and we'll exit
the loop and a contains all the edges of
the minimum spanning tree now let's look
at the code in the main function I
create a graph that contains the
vertices of ABCDEF and a bunch of edge
that connects the vertices essentially
I'm creating a graph like this
and then I call the function prim which
implements the Primera ISM the graph is
represented with a vector of vertices
and a vector of edge I've also added
another function adjacent which will
find all the adjacent vertices of this
vertex and both the adjacent vertex and
the edge that's connecting to it are
returned this is the prim function that
implements the plume algorithm we have
three hash tables a will contain all the
edges of the minimum spanning tree
parent and the key are used for
computation all the parents are
initialized to now all the keys I
initialize to infinite then we choose a
as our root and set its key to be 0 and
create a queue which is a copy of all
the vertices then we start looping we
find that U which is the vertex in queue
with the smallest key here I use the STL
algorithm of ming element and a lambda
function to do the job and then i'll
remove you from queue here I use arrays
following remove idiom if you are not
familiar with all these you are
recommended to watch my STR playlist if
the parent of you is not now we'll save
the edge between you and the parent of
you as one edge of the minimum spanning
tree then we find all the vertices that
is adjacent to you
and if the weight of the edge is less
than the key of the vertex then we'll
update the parent of the vertex as well
as the key of the vertex so by end of
this while loop a will contain all the
edges of the minimum spanning tree and
at the end I'll print out every edge
that is saved in a now let's run the
program as you see all the edges of the
minimum spanning tree are printed out
lastly let's look at the complexity of
this algorithm this wire loop is in the
order of the number of vertices and both
the find function and the remove
function are in the order of number of
vertices and this find function is also
in order of vertices and the find
adjacent is in the order of number of
edges so for a space graph where the
number of edges is less than the number
of vertices which is more often in
reality the complexity of this algorithm
is in the order of V square that's all
for today feel free to subscribe to my
channel and check out the other videos I
have bye-bye