hello everyone today we will talk about
disjoint sets which is a very useful
data structure for graph algorithms
suppose we have a universe of items
which we want to manage with disjoint
sets disjoint sets is a group of sets
where no item can be in more than one
set so each item can belong to only one
set as an example this is an example of
disjoint sets we have four disjoint sets
as well as 2s 3s 4s 3 contains 2 items
as well as 2's for each contains only
one item disjoint sets support at least
two operations find and a union which is
also known as find a union algorithm
find will take one item as a parameter
and then return the disjoint set this
item belongs to
so find D will return as 3 because D is
an element in s 3 Union takes two
disjoint sets as parameter and as a
result those two disjoint sets will be
merged into one set so the result of
union s 1 s 2 is this both s 1 and s 2
are merged into the same disjoint set s
1 and both a and C are items inside s 1
so this is an example of disjoint sets
and what kind of operations that it can
do the next question to consider is how
do we implement a disjoint set there are
different ways to implement disjoint
sets the most commonly used is she based
disjoint sets or disjoint set forests so
this is an example of tree based
disjoint sets for tree based disjoint
sets each set is a key so as three is a
tree and each item has a pointer that
points to another item a set is
identified by the loot of the tree the
loot of S 3 is B and the loot of s 1 is
a the loot of s 2 is C loot has a unique
attribute that its pointer is pointing
to itself so all the loots can be
identified by their self pointing
pointers when we can't find D we'll find
the parent of D which is B and B is
representing s 3 so we claim that we
found the disjoint set of D is s 3 and
when we call Union s 2 s 1 we're merging
s 2 and s 1 into one disjoint set so the
result is this as 2 is gone and C is no
longer a root both a and C belong to s 1
and s 1 is represented by its loot a
and then if we call union s1 s3 we are
merging s1 s3 into one disjoint set and
that'll result is this the elements of
ABCD or belong to the disjoint set s3
and s3 is represented by its root B now
let's consider what's the complexity of
the tree-based disjoint set union is
very fast because for Union we only need
to change one pointer for example the
point of a originally was pointing to
itself and now it points to B and we
have finished the merging so Union only
takes constant time find take the time
of the depth if we try to find that
disjoint set of C first we find its
parent a and then find its parent B so
the time of find is proportional to the
depth of the chi-chi based disjoint set
can be easily implemented with pointers
so if we have an item whose data
structure is like this it has some kind
of data and there has a pointer that
points to its parent which is another
item so with this we can easily
implement the tree-based disjoint set
but sometimes this approach of using
pointers is not so convenient for
example what if the item data structure
doesn't have a pointer and this item is
defined in a third-party library
therefore you cannot change it then
things become difficult you have to
create a wrapper class of this item and
adding a pointer inside of the wrapper
there is another way of implementing a
tree that doesn't use pointers at all
which is using hash table using hash
table has the advantage that it is not
intrusive we don't have to change the
data structure of the item to add
pointers if it doesn't have one we can
use the item as is so for today's coding
demo I'm going to use hash table to
implement sea-based
disjoint sets this is a C++
implementation example of disjoint set
so in this case the type of our items is
char and the universe of items contain 5
chars ABCDE
the key data in the disjoint set is this
parent which is a hash table and this
hash table defines the parental
relationship between the chars
and in the constructor we take each item
of the universe and set its parent to be
itself which means we'll have 5 disjoint
sets and each set contains only one item
and then we set the parent of D to be B
and as a result of that B and D are in
the same set and B is the loot so
essentially we have created this
disjoint sets B and D are in the same
set and AC e are in their own set the
find function take an item as parameter
and the return the disjoint set where
this item belong to if the parent of
this item is this item itself which
means this item is the loot and the loot
is a representative of the disjoint set
so we can claim that we have found the
disjoint set and return the loot
otherwise we continue to find the parent
of the item
the union function takes two disjoint
sets as parameter and those two disjoint
sets are represented with their roots
and what this function does is it sets
the second dilute to be the parent of
the first aleut as a result the first
load is no longer allude and that the
second dilute is the root of both
disjoint sets so they are merged in the
main function I have created a disjoint
set D s and if I do D s start find C
this should return C because C belongs
to a single item disjoint set as you
shown in this picture and then I do the
s dot you mean C a so I'm merging the
disjoint set of C and the disjoint set
of a so as a result a and C are in the
same set so in the picture basically we
have done this a is the new root of this
new set
and now if we do D s dot find C again
this will get turn a and if we do D s
Union a a is the new loot so it
represents that set and we Union a ways
B and the B is the loot of the set that
contains B and D so as a result is a C
be B are in the same set so in the
picture what we have done is this
so this is how a disjoint set data
structure can be used now let's analyze
if there's any way we can improve the
performance of disjoint sets the union
function only takes constant time so
there is no room to improve the Union
function but the find function is slower
it is in the order of the depth of the
tree so the deeper the tree grows the
slower the find will become so if we can
find a way to let the tree more grow
towards the side then grow in downward
then we can flatten the tree and we can
improve the performance of the find
function let's look at our code so where
do the trees grow the trees grow in the
union function and here I just randomly
choose the second elute to be the new
root so if I'm unlucky my tree will grow
deeper and deeper and the find function
will become slower and slower
now let me implement some strategy in
choosing the new root if I always choose
the loot of the deeper G to be the new
loot then the tree will not grow deeper
let me repeat if I always choose the
root of the deeper G to be the new root
then the tree will not grow deeper and
that is a very good news for us but in
order to do that we need something to
record the depth of the trees so let's
do it
will create another on order the map
which is from char to int it's called
rank and this is to record
the depth of cheese initially we made
every disjoint set to contain only one
item so that means the length of each
key is zero and after we merged D and B
the length of B becomes one and that the
Union function needs to be more
complicated so this is my new Union
function remember will choose the loot
of a deeper G to be the new loot so if
the rank of set one is bigger than set
two which is set one to be the new loot
if the rank of set two is bigger than
set one then we'll choose set two to be
the new root else if both three are of
the same depth then we just randomly
choose and set two as the new loot but
the rank of set 2 will increase by one
so only when both trees are of the same
depth the tree will grow deeper by one
now we'll have much more flat entries
than previous implementation therefore
we'll have better performance with the
find function that's all for today feel
free to subscribe to my channel and
check out the other videos I have
bye-bye