hello everyone today we are going to
talk about K Niki look up what is it say
we have a namespace a and inside a we
defined a struct X and the function G in
the main function I defined a x1 of X
and then invoke G X 1 this code will
print out calling a : column G there's
no question about that
however if I remove a column column and
only calling G X 1 what will happen you
may expect that the compiler will error
out saying cannot find a function called
G because the function G is only defined
inside the namespace a however this code
will not only compile it will still
print out calling it a column column G
it turns out when the compiler see the
function G it will not only search the
function G in the current scope and the
global scope it will also search the
function in the scope where its
parameter type is defined in this case
the type of its parameter is X and X is
defined in namespace a so the compiler
will search the G function in the
namespace a that is how this G function
is found this is a called chaining
lookup or argument dependant
lookup ADL
when can you look up we have increased
the function name search scope so if I
have another function it's a global
function also called G this code will
not compile because there are two G
function visible inside the main
function example two we have a class C
now C is a class it's not a namespace
anymore
inside the see we have a struct Y and a
static function H in the main function I
defined a Y and call H Y this will print
out calling c colon column H there's no
question about that
however if I'll remove C column column
what will happen since we have clinic
lookup when the compiler see the
function H it was searched the function
in the scope where the type of its
parameter is defined so it was searched
inside C and find H right no actually
the clinic lookup only applies to
namespace it cannot reach its tentacles
into a class so this is an error
example three now we have two namespaces
namespace a same as before has the
struct X and the function G namespace
see also has a function G in the
function J I created at X and called GX
the main function will invoke the
function J what will happen this code
will not compile when the compiler try
to resolve the function call of G it
definitely can see this function G
however because of the clinic lookup it
can also see this function of G so the
compiler doesn't know which one to call
it's an ambiguous code to function G now
if I change see from a namespace to a
class
now what will happen this code will
compile and print out calling C column
column G why because when the compiler
tries to find function G it will first
search it inside Class C and if the
function G is found it will stop
searching only when the G is not found
inside of the class C the compiler will
look at the global scope and the use
Kanak lookup so if this function is not
defined inside of the Class C this code
will still compile but print out calling
a column column G so the conclusion we
can draw from this example is the class
member functions are more tightly bound
with each other than with any other
functions now let's see we have another
class B and this G function is being
moved to be
and Class C is publicly derived from B
now what will happen this code will
compile and print out calling B colon
column G so the conclusion is a member
function from parent class also has a
higher priority than any outside the
function name hiding last time we've
talked about name hiding for classes and
today we're going to talk about the name
hiding for namespaces we have a
namespace a and inside a we have a G
function which takes an integer
parameter and inside a there's an STD
namespace
see see also has a G function but this G
function has no parameter and the j
function invokes g8 and ultimately the J
function is invoked you may expect when
the compiler cg8 it should invoke this G
function because they are all under the
umbrella of namespace a so this G
function should be visible inside
namespace C but actually it is not this
code will not compile because this G
function is shadowed by C's on G
function even though they have different
parameter signature this is named hiding
remember how to overcome name heidi
using the using declaration
now this code will compile so far this
example is very similar to the classic
example of name hiding that we've talked
about last time now let me bring
something different let's say the a has
a struct X and G is taking X as a
parameter and let's remove the using
declaration and define X X G X now
according to the name hiding law this G
function will be hidden by C's on G
function so this code will not compile
right run this code will compile and
print out calling a G it is true that
this G function will be hidden biases on
G function according to the name hiding
rule however there's another rule that
kicks in which is the technique look up
with kenick look up the compiler will
look for the G function in thus in the
space where X is defined so this code
will compile even though we don't have
the using declaration this is something
different from the classic example a
summary of name lookup sequence when
working with namespaces a compiler will
first such a name under current scope
then go to next enclosed scope and then
next enclosed scope until finally it
goes to the global scope to search the
name
and when working with classes the
compatible first search in current class
scope and then parent class scope and
then grandparent scope and finally go to
the global scope name hiding will happen
when a higher priority scope defines a
function with the same name as a
function in the lower priority scope to
override the sequence of name lookup or
to bring some hidden name back to
current scope with namespaces there are
two way to do it one is with qualifier
or using declaration another one is
using connect lookup with classes
there's only one way to do it which is
the qualifier or using integration you
cannot use connect look up for classes
thank you for watching subscribe to my
channel so you will be updated when I
post a new video or you can go to my
channels home page and click on
playlists to see other videos that are
more free
bye bye