hello welcome to the first session of
C++ advanced today we are going to talk
about four functions that could be
generated by compiler if you don't
declare them by yourself the copy
constructor copy assignment operator
destructor default constructor there's a
additional rule about the default
constructor which is edible generate
will be generated only if there is no
constructor declared at all suppose I
write a class dog with empty definition
the class dog is equivalent to a class
like this the compiler will fearing the
four functions for me since I don't have
them defined copy constructor copy
assignment operator default constructor
and the destructor now you may imagine
that the compiler generated functions
are emptied functions that doing nothing
for this particular case they are doing
nothing because the dark class is so
trivial but for any real world class
there there will not be empty they'll do
their jobs
the copy constructor um will do a member
by member initialization it will use the
members from right hand side dog to
initialize every member of its of where
they stock the copy assignment operator
will do a member by member copying it
will copy the members from right hand
start aside dog to the stock
the default constructor will call base
classes default constructor and the data
members default constructor and that the
destructor is doing the opposite it will
call it base classes destructor and the
data members destructor these are the
things that the compiler generated
function will do now you may want to ask
the question what if the compiler
generator function is unable to do the
job they are supposed to do for example
the copy assignment operator will do a
member by member copying what if one of
the members is a Const or reference
remember the tungsten reference they
cannot be copied or they can only be
initialized then what does the compiler
do the compiler will simply do not
generate this function and similarly for
a default constructor it will call the
base classes Dvorkin jump what whatever
the base class doesn't have a default
constructor then again this function
will be not be generated or destructor
or every class have a destructor so it
should have no problem called the base
classes each doctor enter the data
members destructor right well not
exactly
what if the base classes destructor is
not public it's a private district then
again this destructor cannot be
generated
so the compiler generator functions
sometimes are really handy to use but
you need to keep these things in mind if
you are relying on the compiler to
generate this function for you some
other nodes are the compiler general
functions are public and inline they are
generated only if they are needed that
means if they are not used at all in the
function with other functions then they
will not be generated even if the
compiler is capable of generating them
now let's look at a less trivial class
dog the dog has a M name which is the
name of the dog it is a stream and the
dogs constructor takes a name as the
parameter and the default name is Bob
and the dog has a destructor in the main
function I create a dog one with the
name Henry and then I create dok2 and
then assign doc one to duck to the
output of this simple program is Henry's
bone Bob is born Henry is destroyed hell
is destroyed the reason henry is
destroyed it twice is because duck two
was created as bob and the destroyed as
hell because dog 1 is assigned to duck
too
now let's examine what functions are
generated by compiler in this particular
example if the car Bay constructed
generated by compiler no because the
copy constructor is not used in our main
function so it will not be generated
it's a copy assignment operator
generated by the compiler
we used copy assignment operator over
here
and our dog does not have a copy
assignment operator defined so that the
compiler will gladly generate that
function for us and so it's yes
destructor the structure is always be
used but a dog already have a destructor
defined so the answer is no the compiler
no need to generate one the default
constructor the default constructor is
used over here and the dog already
defined a default constructor over here
now many people have the concept that
the default constructor is a constructor
that has no parameter that is wrong
concept a default constructor is a
constructor that can work without any
Queen without any parameter so this is
our default constructor so the answer is
no because we already have a disjunct
default constructor
now suppose I change the M name member
from a string to a reference to a string
now what will happen to this code
this code will no longer compile because
here we are using a copy assignment
operator that's generated by compiler
and the compiler generated copy
assignment operator there's a member by
member copy since the dog has a member
which is a reference this member cannot
be copied so the compiler will not
generate this operator for us this code
will not compile
so another thing about this example is
this kind of class cannot be used by
with the standard library container
because standard library container
requires the combined the contain need
to be copy sign label when the copy
constructible so this is our job make
now let's look at our second example we
have a new class color and the dog have
the data member em cover which is of
type color and in the main function I
create a dot dot one what do you think
the output of this program is you may
pause the video and think about it this
code will not compile to give a compiler
error that says no matching function for
call to dog dog how did this happen
whether this error message come from
when I create dog one I'm calling the
tox default constructor for dog 1 and if
since my dog doesn't have a default
constructor the compiler will try to
create a default constructor for me and
we know that the compiler generated a
default constructor will call the data
members default constructor in this case
we'll call em colors default constructor
however the color doesn't have a default
constructor either so the compiler will
try to generate the default constructor
for color first since color already have
a constructor that takes a stream
parameter the compiler is not able to
generate a default constructor for color
as a result the compiler is not able to
generate a default constructor for dog
either that is why we got this message
no matching function call to
dogs default constructor and that the
candidates are detox copy constructor we
know that copy constructor is that the
second constructor that compiler
generates so if if we remove the
parameter from four colors constructor
then this code will compile and the
output will be color is born now let's
add a second data member for Doc it's a
reference to stream if you remember from
previous example that a stream data
member a reference data member in the
class will prevent the compiler from
generating copy assignment operator for
the class since even in this example we
are only using the default constructor
so we should be fine right
not exactly the compiler generated a
default constructor will call the
default constructor for the data member
of data members of the dog that is good
however what the default constructor
doesn't do is to initialize the data
members for the dog so in this case and
name is constructed but not initialized
and we know that c++ standard requires
that all reference need to be
initialized because reference cannot be
reassigned so the only way to assign a
variable reference is through
initialization because m name is not
initialized so this code will not
compile finally there's a update in C++
instead C++ 11 there's a new way to
define the default constructor it is
done by this this gives me a way to use
the compiler generated default
constructor even though I have defined
other constructors already so this
should be a very handy feature that's
all for today's class thank you for
watching and you're welcome to give me
any feedbacks in the comments so that I
can improve my class bye bye