hello everyone today we'll talk about
using virtual destructors in polymorphic
base classes let's look at our example
we have a cast dog and dogs destructor
brings out dog destroyed yellow dog
derived from dog and the yellow dogs
destructor prints out yellow dog
destroyed and here I'm using a factory
design pattern I use a dog factory class
to be the centralized place of creating
dogs and I have a static function create
a yellow dog which creates a yellow dog
and you turn it as a tox pointer and it
also has other functions to create other
types of dogs in the main function I
have a dog's pointer P D equal to talk
factory create yellow dog and after I've
done something with PD eventually I
delete PD let's run the program as you
see when PD gets deleted only the tox
destructor is called that is very bad
because we have created a yellow dog and
in the end only part of the yellow dog
is destroyed we have to make sure that
the yellow dogs own destructor also
needs to be invoked this is why we need
a virtual
destructor for the base classes and now
if we run the program both yellow dog
and the dogs destructor are invoked so
the conclusion we are getting from this
example is if the class is meant to be
used in a polymorphic way such as in
this case we are creating a yellow dog
and then castellated into a tox pointer
then the base class must have a virtual
destructor to ensure that destructors
are invoked appropriately if a class has
any sort of virtual function like a bark
function then it is most likely that
this class will be used polymorphically
which means most likely it will need a
virtual destructor if for some reason
you really don't want to have a virtual
destructor then there is a second way to
do it share the pointer of dog
and the inside of the create a yellow
dot function I'm going to create a
shared pointer of yellow dog so I create
a shared point of yellow dog and then
casted into shared pointer of dog in the
main function
I do shared pointer of dog PD and I
don't need to delete the PD anymore
because the shared pointer will be
responsible to delete the object and in
this case I don't even need the virtual
destructor and let's run the program
again as you see both yellow dog and
dogs
destructors are invoked note that you
can only use the shared pointer to
perform this kind of magic if you are
using unique pointer it won't do the job
unique pointer will only invoke the dogs
destructor the last thing I want to
point out is all the classes in st l
have no virtual destructor so you need
to be very careful when you are
inheriting from them one thing you can
do is try to use shared pointer as much
as possible for the classes that is
derived from the STL classes
that's all for the day feel free to
subscribe to my channel and check out
the other videos I have bye-bye