hello everyone today we are going to
talk about a pitfall that happens when
you have a class that owns another
object through its pointer what do I
mean by that here is example of this we
have a class person and this person has
a private data member which is a pointer
to a stream key name and in this
person's constructor it create a new
string object with this name and in the
person's destructor it deletes that key
name so this is what I mean by one class
is only another class by pointer in this
case the person owns the stream through
its pointer that P name note that if the
person has the pointer of P name but it
is not responsible of creating and the
destructing of the object of p name then
this person is not owning that object of
p name it merely has acquaintance with
that object of p name and this person
also have a print name function which
prints out the name and in the main
function I created a vector of person
called persons and then I create a
person whose name is George and push it
back into the person's the vector and
since I'm using pushing push back so the
person's thought back function will
return a reference to the last person in
the vector namely the person George and
then I invoke the print name function
from that person so this code looks so
innocent I create a person push it into
vector and the line codes print name
function what could go wrong if I run
the program
it actually crashed and if we look at
the coding stack it crashed at at the
point where the print name function is
called so what happened let's analyze
what has happened with this line of code
what happened over here is actually
different for signals past eleven
standard and for the older standard
today will mainly talk about the older
standard and in the future we'll cover
C+ 11 with the old standard this simple
line of code actually involves three
operations step one
this person George is constructed step
two
a copy of George is saved in the vector
persons step three
this person George is destroyed there
are a couple of things that we need to
pay attention to first of all this
person George and this person in the
vector are not the same person they are
identical but they are not the same
person that different objects one person
is copy of the other and secondly when
we make a copy of this person George and
saved in the vector we are making a
share low copy of this person George
because that's what the default copy
constructor would do so as a result of
that this person George's pointer P name
and that this person in the vectors
pointer P name are pointing to the same
object of stream and the lastly this
person George is our value which means
it will be destroyed at the end of this
statement and when the person George is
destroyed it will call the destructor
and we will delete the object that is
pointing to by the P name pointer and as
a direct result of that the person in
the vector whose pointer P name will be
pointing to a deleted object of stream
so when we call the person in the
vectors print name function it will
access an object that is already deleted
that is why this program has crashed
so what should we do with this kind of
class there are two solution that you
can use solution number one is define
copy constructor and copy assignment
operator for deep copy so here let's
define a copy constructor right hand
side value and we'll make a deep copy
and since we need to access this private
data member so we need to provide an
accessor to that data member
and we should do the same thing for copy
assignment operator
and this one should also do deep copying
and now if we learn the program again it
went through okay and the second
solution for this is delete copy
constructor and copy assignment operator
and we can do that by making the copy
private functions so that nobody else
can use them and better yet we can
remove the definition of these two
functions so that even the person's
children and friends cannot use these
two functions so now we have two
solutions solution one and a solution to
which one should we prefer personally I
prefer the second solution delete the
copy constructor and the copy assignment
operator if you think about it there's
rarely the case where you have to define
a copy constructor and a copy assignment
operator one common place where you want
to define these two functions is when
you are working with STL containers STL
container requires there contain need to
be copy constructible and copy
assignable but we can easily work around
this by saving an object's pointer in
the containers instead of for the object
itself and when we push back we push it
back a pointer of the person and when we
call the print named function we use the
pointers syntax
and of course we need to remember to
delete all the objects later on so this
will work as we expected however even
though we can live without the copy
construct and copy assignment operator
sometimes we do need to make a copy of
object how can we do that if we don't
have these two functions we can define a
clone function
so this chrome function will return an
identical copy of this object itself you
can find all the places where the
copying has happened by grabbing the
function name clone of all your code
the problem with copy constructor is it
is making the copying implicit the
copying can happen implicitly
when an object is passed as a parameter
to another function or being returned
from another function an implicit AKOP
eing is oftentimes the place where the
bugger is introduced so our solution to
is delete copy constructor and copy
assignment operator and the define clone
function so in summary anytime you have
one object owning another object through
its pointer like this you have to do one
of these two things first one is define
copy construct and copy assignment
operator for deep copying and second one
is delete the copy constructor and a
copy assignment operator
thank you for watching feel free to
subscribe to my channel and check out
the other videos I have see you next
time