hello everyone today's topic is how to
define your own new handle last session
we've talked about how to customize
operate and new and operate a delete
from the wave input it free and talk
about what is what new handler is and
today let's start with the review a new
handler is a function that's invoked
when an operate a new field to allocate
memory its main purpose is to help the
memory allocation to succeed the
function set new handler installs a new
handler and the lieutenant current new
handler
this is an example of operate a new
implementation that we talked about last
week last assertion to demo the what the
operator new typically does inside the
function there is an infinite loop and
first thing it try to do is allocate the
memory of the size size if the
allocations succeed it will return the
memory and it's done otherwise it will
fetch the new handler
and check if the new handle is the valid
or is a null pointer if it's not a null
pointer it will just invoke the new
handler hopefully it can do something
nice to free up the memory and then go
back to the loop and try to allocate
memory again new handle can if the new
handle is now a bad a log exception in
the throw new handler can do a lot of
things but one thing it must do is to
exit the infinite loop and there are
three exit from the infinite loop one is
return the memory and second thing is
flow a bad allocate exception lastly
that new handler itself can either throw
exception or terminate the program
immediately
so these are five options that our new
handler must do oh it must do at least
one of the things first make memory
available so that next run of memory
allocation could be succeed second
install different new handle if the
current and new handler can not do
anything to free up the memory and maybe
a different new handler could third I'll
install the new handle set the new
handle to now which means I can do it
cannot do anything about the memory
anymore so it will just throw a bad a
log exception number four
instead of let operate a new to throw
the exception and you handle again
through exception self of the bad a log
or any exception that is derived from a
dialog last option is to terminate the
program
so let's look at some examples in this
example in the main function I try to
create a gigantic array of integers and
of course my host machine cannot handle
that so it will print out extra
exceptions so what's happening here is
because I haven't installed any new
Handler and by default the new handle is
now so when then operate a new test
whether the new handle is now it is now
so it's just throw exceptions so output
will be terminate called
after throwing instances of bad I look
our second example I define a new
function called no more mem and in the
main function I install the normal man
function to be the new Handler and then
again as before I create a gigantic
integer array and this time because I
already set a new handler and what the
new handler does is print out some
message and then terminate the program
the last option
so the output will be unable to allocate
memory Bo
what I have done here is I set a global
new handler to be a normal man which
means any memory allocation fail we'll
call this new handle one question you
might want to ask is can I set a class
specific new handler
a new handler can invoked only when the
memory allocation allocation for a
particular class fail the answer is yes
we can implement that in tsipras pass by
overloading the operator new so this
example my dog class have a function no
more ma'am no member dot and I've
overloaded the operator new over here
and the main purpose of the operating
new overloading is to three things
number one I set the new handler to be
no mem for dog and secondly I called
operate the new as before as usual this
will allocate memory for dog
lastly I restore the new Hendra to
whatever that was before because the
gnome m4 dog new handle is only for dog
so anybody else after that should use
one whatever was that new handler before
so this is how the new hinderer
class-specific new handler can be
implement there's a small problem with
this part this program can you see what
it is
the problem is when then operate a new
fail fail to allocate the memory it will
invoke the new handler which is the
gnome m4 dog and then no man for dog
will throw exceptions so that means the
original new handler will not be
restored so we need to copy this next
line to over here and in the gnome m4
dock function before I throw exception I
want to restore the original handler
that will complete the implementation
that's all thank you if you have any
question any comments please leave
comments in below