hello everyone starting from today we
are going to have a Celia of talk about
the namespace and the name lookup we'll
start with some basics and then move on
to some more advanced stuff sea plasmas
namespace has an important keyword using
this keyword can be used in two ways
number one is using directive it is to
bring all namespace members into current
scope so that you can use them without a
qualifier in front of them
so if I have using namespace stood I'm
bringing every name understood into
current scope a second usage is using
declaration using declaration itself can
be used in two ways a it brings one
specific namespace member into current
scope so if I have using stood out after
that I can use the out without the
qualifier B brings a member from base
class to current classes scope so this
is working with class and not namespace
using the R active can only work with
name space using declaration can work
with either namespace or class now let's
look at example is classes in it we have
a Class B and Class B has a public
function f we have a class D which is
derived from B it has a function G and
function H
this is a use interactive and this is a
using decoration using deductive and a
using declaration when working with
namespaces they can be used either under
global scope like this or in the local
function scope like this this is a using
decoration for class member it brings
the function f from the parent class
class b into current class with public
access you might be wondering why do we
need to do that isn't the function f
inherited by D already the class D is
privately derived from B which means
these public function becomes this
private function so f is this private
function if I don't use the decoration
using declaration then I create a D and
call d f8 this code will not compile
because F is a private function however
after using the using declaration for
function f is called will compile
you may have noticed the using
declaration for class member is used in
the class scope it cannot be used in a
local scope it cannot be used in a
global scope and this guy is the only
one can be used in the class cope so if
I have a using declaration of a class
member in the global scope this is
illegal
similarly if I have a using declaration
of namespace member in the class scope
this is also illegal
if I have a using elective
in the class cope this is also illegal
last example again we have the base
Class B and the derived class D now D is
publicly derived from B so it will
inherit B's public function as its own
public function the B has a function f
with with the integer parameter D has a
function f with no parameter in the main
function I created a D and then called
df8 you would expect the function f of B
which takes an integer parameter will be
invoked but it will not this code will
not compile it turns out this function f
is shadowed by this own function f this
is called named hiding to overcome name
hiding we could use using decoration
now this code will compile finally I
want to introduce you anonymous
namespace anonymous namespace is a
namespace that doesn't have a name and
as a result everything inside of the
namespace can be accessed within the
same file so in the main function I can
call the each function as if using the
elective is included implicitly for the
anonymous namespace however you cannot
call the a function from another file so
this is effectively similar to having
defined a global static function of H
however this has the additional benefits
of namespace for example if I have
another function G and also have another
function G inside of the namespace and
when H function called G it will call
the local version of the G and not the
global version that's all for today next
time we will talk about connect lookup
keep tuned