software engineering is largely about
code reuse in C++ there are mainly two
ways of code reuse one is inheritance
one is composition so which one should
we use we had a light touch on this
topic in previous videos and today we
are going to dive deeper into it let's
look at our example we have a class
based dog and Bulldog and Shepherd dog
are derived from the base dog the base
stock defines some common activities and
poor dog and she'll talk we'll call
these common activities to perform more
tasks I've seen this kind of code
structuring a lot of places and honestly
I don't like it
the first problem I have is with the
name base talk almost every C++ program
that I've seen there's always a class or
even a bunch of classes which are named
based something with inheritance the
class names should symbolize a easier
relationship between the base class and
the derived class and in our example the
Bulldog is a base dog which doesn't make
any sense
what is the base dog anyway besides the
name base top is not extendable what if
later on I decide to create a new class
and derive base dog from that new class
what should I name the new class should
I name it base base dog I guess the
biggest problem I have with the base dog
name is it reviews the implementation
detail it will reviews the fact that
this class based on is used to derive
other classes
a class name is part of the interface
and when the interface reveals the
implementation details we are losing all
the benefits of abstraction however this
is not a problem if the base talk is
only a internal class and not exposed on
the interface so instead of call coded
based something why don't we just call
it something instead of calling it based
on why don't we just call it dog
now Bulldog is a kind of dog and the
shepherd dog is another kind of dog it
makes much more sense this way and it's
extendable a dog can be derived from an
animal animal can be derived from
organism so on and so forth some people
may argue yeah yeah but these are names
there are cosmetic changes in software
engineering good naming is not cosmetic
good naming is a critical element of a
good software design we should always
strive for precise and self-explaining
names for our classes our functions and
our variables now let's move on to the
main line of today's topic the dog
defines some common activities and
Bulldog shepherd dog we use these common
activities to perform more tasks so this
is the example of code reuse with
inheritance
and let's look at how we can achieve the
same kind of code we use with
compensation we have a new class
activity manager and all the common
activities that originally defined in
dog are moved to the activity manager
every dog have a pointer to the activity
manager P act manager and that they
reuse the code of the common activities
through the P act manager this is a code
reuse with composition structure
how does it look comparing to the
inheritance example on the surface it
seems like the composition is worse
because it has more lines of code and it
introduces a new class however the
composition is actually a much better
structure for code reuse let's discuss
why number one composition has less code
coupling between the reused code and the
double user of the code inheritance
implies more coat covering between the
child class under the parent class the
reasons are a the child class
automatically inherits all the parent
classes public members so whether you
like it or not the child classes
interface is bloated with the parent
classes interface however with the
composition you can always pick the
things that you want to use and bring
that into your interface be the child
class can access parent classes
protected members in other words it can
access the parents internals so in a
sense that in the inheritance breaks
encapsulation
there are two peaks the enemy of
encapsulation in C++ what are they
number one is friend and number two is
inheritance so friends and children fix
the enemy of your privacy it's a
philosophy of life the second reason why
composition is better than inheritance
is dynamic binding the inheritance
relationship is bound at compile time
once you pass the compile time the
relationship cannot be change it animal
however the composition relationship can
be bound either at compile time or at
one time through polymorphism and the
dynamic binding so we have a outdoor
activity manager and a indoor activity
manager both of them are derived from
the activity manager since each dog has
a pointer to activity manager we can
switch between the outdoor and indoor
activity manager easily during the
runtime
lastly composition has more flexible
code constructor say you have many types
of dog and many types of activity
managers with composition you can make
arbitrary combination of the dogs and
activity managers there is no limit on
how you can combine a dog with an
activity manager if you really want one
dog can even have multiple instances of
activity manager at the same time with
the inheritance you can only have one
instance of an apparent at a time
so combine those three let's code
covering
dynamic binding and the flexible code
constructor we declare that composition
is a better structure for code reuse
than inheritance inheritance is good for
other things but not for code reuse
that's all for today see you next time
bye bye