hello everyone last time we've talked
about the four functions that compiler
automatically generates for us if we
don't create them ourselves the copy
constructor copy assignment operator
destructor and the default constructor
that is nice it can save us some effort
and time to create them
however the compiler generator functions
are not always useful and sometimes they
are even dangerous to use for example we
have a class open file which represents
a file being opened and since the
compiler will automatically generate
generator the default constructor for us
I can do Open File F and this will call
the compiler generator default function
let's run it it can run successfully
from begin to end
although it does nothing and in this
case the compiler generated default
constructor is useless to us because in
order to open a file we at least need a
file name say I don't want my client to
use my open file this way and I want to
disallow that how can I do it for
default constructor it is actually easy
as long as I define a constructor that
takes any parameters then the compiler
will not generate the default
constructor for me
so here I create another constructor
that takes a string of file name and
then it prints some message and let's
run it as you see the compile failed
that is because no match function for
code to the default constructor so the
difficulty for constructor is not there
anymore
now in order to create a open file I
need to provide a parameter
let's call screening Oh file and then
run it now
it compiles and it runs okay it opens a
file file now in this case the compiler
generated function is just useless
but it doesn't harm us in any way but
sometime the compiler generated function
could be dangerous to use for example
saying now I have opened both file for
writing with F and then I create another
open file F 2 which is copy construct
from F this will call the compiler
generated copy constructor for F 2 and F
2 will also write to go file now we have
both F and F 2 writing to both file at
at the same time so the result will be
pretty messy so I want to disallow the
copy constructor from being used what
can I do if you are using super fancy
level already it is pretty easy all you
need to do is that make the copy
constructor to be a deleted function and
run it
the compile failed because there's a
deleted function that being used if
you're using C++ oh three it's not
difficult either all you need to do is
make the copy constructor a private
function and we don't define the
function now let's run it it fails
because the the copy constructor
function is private some of you may be
clever enough to say hey this is not
enough the open files member function
can still use the copy constructor say
it has a function called g and g creates
another open file f - f this will work
right let's learn it build still failed
but now it fills with a message that she
prefers forbids ticket Declaration of G
with no type although function G can
access the copy constructor alright
since we only have declared the copy
constructor we have not defined it so
function G cannot find that the body of
the copy constructor so as a result
nobody can use the copy constructor
anymore and we can use the same method
to disable the copy assignment operator
also this method can be used to disable
any function the default constructor
destructor or say the open file has
inherited a function called writeline
and we don't want the open file to use
that function right line we can use this
method to turn that function off
speaking of destructor is this a good
idea to really turn off the destructor
like this now we have defined the open
files destructor to be private and we
have not defined it so nobody can use
the open files destructor anymore it is
really a good idea apparently not an
object must be destructed one way or
another otherwise some resource is
doomed to be leaked so we have to give a
body to the destructor however some time
it does make sense to have a private
destructor let's remove all the others
and take a closer look at the private
the destructor now we only have a
constructor and a destructor and if we
compile the program it will fail because
the destructor is private since the open
file F is stored on stack once the F is
out of scope the stack unwind and F will
be destructed and the since main
function has no access to the private
function of destructor of open file this
will not compile
so this kind of open file is invincible
it cannot be destroyed by anyone else
except itself and its friends yeah
friends are worse than enemies this kind
of a mechanism sometimes are used by
reference counting shared pointers a
reference counting shared pointer counts
the number of pointers that points to
itself and once that count reached zero
it commits suicide in our example of
Open File since it doesn't commit
suicide and it doesn't have friends so
we have to provide a public interface
let's call it destroy me to delete this
object and in the main function we can
call F dot destroy me to destroy the
open file F this sounds it alright let's
run it
oops it's still failed and it still
reports the same error the open file the
destructor is private now what happened
since F is stored on stack even though
we have called F dot destroy me to
destroy the F when the stack unwind F
will be destroyed again so the private
the destructor will be invoked anyway
then how can we use an object like Open
File which has a private destructor we
could
stall the F on stack and then call F
destroy me now let's run it
Bravo now the open file is destructed so
the conclusion is a class like open file
which has our private destructor can
only be stored on heap it cannot be
stored on stack this sometime can be
useful in the embedded programming where
the stack size is small and the people
often time get a stack overflow
you could let the heavyweight classes to
have private the destructor so that they
can only be stored on the heap you kind
of enforced that these heavy with
objects not to be stored on the stack a
summary of disallowing functions for the
constants 11 you can always use the
keyword delete to delete the function
for simplify so 3 you can declare the
function to be private but not define it
private the destructor can be used to
force the object not to be stored on
stack that's all for today thank you for
watching feel free to subscribe to my
channel so when I post a new video you
will be updated or you can go to my
channels home page and see what I'm
offering today bye bye