hello everyone welcome to learning C++
today's topic is user-defined implicit
type conversion in C++ there are two
categories of type conversion the
standard type conversion and user
defined type computed the standard type
conversion convert objects between the
built-in types such as an integer float
pointer user-defined the type conversion
in the conversion between two classes or
between a class and a building type both
extend the type conversion and the user
defined type conversion can be implicit
or explicit explicitly type of
conversion is also called casting and
casting itself is another big topic that
deserve a session of its own so today's
session we're going to focus on implicit
type conversion category a implicit
standard type conversion this one is
relatively simple let's look at some
examples I have a character C and then I
implicitly convert C into integer I this
is called integral motion I have another
integer 0 and I convert it to a char
pointer PC this is known as a null
pointer initialization implicit type
conversion also can be used in parameter
passing I have a function which takes an
integer I and I pass it a character C
and the character C is implicitly
converted to integer last example I have
created a yellow dogs pointer and
convert that point into a dog's pointer
PD
please note this is not a user-defined
type of version because here I only
convert the pointers so it's a pointer
type of conversion now let's move on to
the main bulk of today's session
category C which is implicit
user-defined type conversion implicit
user-defined type conversion is defined
by user and the user usually defined
them inside their own class there are
two methods to define the implicit
user-defined type conversion method one
is use constructor that can accept a
single parameter what it does is a
convert other types of object into your
class method two is use type conversion
function which converts an object of
your car into other types let's look at
the example dog a dog has a constructor
which takes a single parameter of a
string it is very important to keep in
mind that a constructor that can take a
single parameter is not just a
constructor it's a constructor plus a
type converter
so um in this case said it converts a
string into a dog so if all you want is
to define a constructor and you don't
care anything about type conversion it
is a good practice to put explicit in
front of your constructor and this way
you tells construct helps compiler that
this is constructor plus explicit type
converter so this way it can help you to
avoid inadvertent type conversion and
without the without the explicit keyword
you tell compiler that this is a
constructor plus a explicit converter
plus a implicit converter so keep that
in mind because now we have a type
conversion from string to a dog in the
main function I create a stream table
name and then convert the table name
into a dog and the print out my name is
Bob now suppose I use the function get
name a lot and I'm really tired of
typing of this function I want to remove
this function to simplify my code what
this mean is I need a mechanism to
convert a dog into a string and
converting an object of my class into
other type I need to I needed a method
to use type conversion function so I'm
defining a type conversion function here
and I don't need the cat named function
anymore now this code will compile
outcome it will convert doc one into a
string which is the dog's name and the
output again is my name is Bob now this
code is very flexible I can define a
string dog to equal to dog long this
will also work it will convert that wire
into a stream dub too but it this kind
of flexibility really good for me if you
look at this code they it seems what I
intend to do is copy a dog one into
another doctor too but I accidentally
use the string instead of dog for dog
two which is of course a bug and my type
conversion function becomes a cup up for
my bug so this leads to an important
design principle when we define our
software API interface
we want to make sure our interface is
easy to use correctly and how to use
incorrectly here by defining too many
implicitly type conversion I'm making my
interface easy to use incorrectly which
is not good
some people claim that type conversion
function should be avoid altogether
personally I believe type combo in
procedure type conversion so you have
its place in C++ however there are a few
two guidelines that we need to follow
number one we should avoid defining
seemingly unexpected conversion and here
convert a stream to a dog is apparently
a seemingly unexpected conversion
another one is avoid defining two-way
impressive type conversion if you've
defined an implicit type conversion from
type A to type of B you probably don't
want to define another conversion run
type beat type a and here by making our
interface hard we use incorrectly
ideally if if the code is used
incorrectly it should not compile and if
the code compiles that means it's using
the interface correctly and of course
this is the ideal goal and not always
achievable implicit the type of
conversion is particularly useful when
creating a numerical type of class such
as a rational class you know will rush
in the class example we have the
rational constructor which takes two
parameters one numerator and one
denominator since both parameter can
have default value this constructor can
with can work with a single parameter a
numerator and since this constructor
doesn't have a explicit keyword in front
of it so that which means this one is a
constructor plus a explicit type
converter plus an implicit type
converter and now in the main function I
converts an integer 23 into a rational
and assign to r1 and second line I
convert integer 2 into another rational
and multiplied to add one and assign the
result to r2 this is great but I want
more I have a rational r3 equal to three
terms of our
when the compiler see this code because
the first parameter 3 is an integer it
will find the global operator multiply
and then convert our one into an integer
and then multiplied to our 3 into 3 and
apparently we don't have a type
conversion that converts a rational into
an integer so this code will not compile
so let's define a conversion for that
integer
turn new do not
now we have a type conversion from
rational to an integer so this line of
code will work however this line code
stopped working why is that when the
compiler look at the operate multiply it
actually find out that there are two
ways to interpret the multiply number
one is same as before use the operator
multiply defined inside of the rational
class and num number two it can also
convert our one into an integer and then
use the global operate multiply for
integer to multiply the two integer
together so we ended up having an
ambiguity this confirms to our design
guideline that a one-way implicitly type
conversion is preferred over a two-way
implicit type conversion now you may say
I really want both lines of code to work
is there a better approach for me yes
there there is a better approach you
could use a non-member operate multiply
that multiply two rationals together and
that things we have that we could remove
the member rationals member multiply as
well as the type conversion function
and now both lines of code will work
that's all for today hope you enjoy the
video bye bye