hello everyone today I'm going to show
you a pitfall in calling virtual
function in constructor or destructor
let's look at our example we have a
class dog and dogs constructor prints
out dog born and dogs bark function
print out I'm just a dog and dog also
has a seek add function in a dog see a
cat big box yellow dog is derived from
dog and the yellow dog is constructor
printout yellow dog born and the yellow
dog box I'm a yellow dog in the main
function I created a yellow dog D and
then called D dot C cat let's run the
program so when I created the yellow
double D it first called the dog's
constructor and the printout dog-bone
and then it called yellow dogs
constructor and cleaned out yellow dot
born and then it caused seed cat and C
cat cause the bulk function and and the
bunk function prints out I'm just a dog
even though this is a yellow dog to help
the dog to be honest we have to make
this bark function virtual the version
is of a function can be inherited so the
yellow dogs bark function automatically
becomes a virtual function but in
practice it is a good idea to always put
a virtual keyword in front of the
function to make it explicit that this
is a virtual function
and now let's learn the program the dog
box I'm a yellow dog so when the Seacat
function invoke the bug function it
realized that this this object is a
yellow dog so it invokes the yellow dogs
function this is the power of dynamic
binding as long as the D is a yellow dog
it will always call a yellow dogs
virtual function today I'm going to show
you a scenario where this idea of
dynamic binding is not working let's say
the bark function is invoked inside the
docs constructor and to see what
happened this spark function prints out
I'm just a dog even though the bark
function is a virtual function and we
know that the object being created is a
yellow dog it is still calling the dogs
bark function so what happened when
yellow dog D is created before it
calling the yellow dogs constructor it
first call the dogs constructor so at
this point the constructor of the yellow
dog is not executed yet in other words
the yellow dog is not constructed yet we
all know it is dangerous to call the
member function of an object that is not
constructed yet unless that function is
a static function so the compiler is
doing the second best thing which is
calling the dogs own bark function so
this Park function behaves like a
non-virtual function when it is imposed
inside a constructor
the conclusion we're getting from this
example is we should avoid calling
virtual function in a constructor the
constructor should do as little as
possible to put the object into a valid
state and that's it calling any fancy
function inside the constructor is not
recommended and at the same idea for
destructor if we have a destructive talk
that also caught the bump function and
run the program
as you see when the destructor of the
dog calling the bark function it also
call the dogs bark function because when
the D gets destroyed it first called the
destructor of the yellow dog and then
call the destructor of the dog so at
this point the yellow dog is already
destroyed and it is not a good idea to
call the member function of something is
already destroyed that's all for today
feel free to subscribe to my channel and
check out the other videos I have
bye-bye