hello everyone today we will talk about
Const with functions say we have a class
dog and dog has an integer of age and
the string of name and the dog has a
constructor that initialized as age and
the name and here the same dog has a
function called set H and which sets H
to the parameter of a and in the main
function I create a dog D and I have an
integer I equal to 9 and then I call d
dot set a GI and print out and then
print out the I so this will print out 9
so far so good
suppose the set H function not only use
a to set H it also makes some change to
the parameter a say it an increment a by
remember the set H function takes the
parameter by reference so when I
increment a it also incremented the
original valuable I so if we learn the
program it prints out 10 because I has
been changed to 10 by the set H function
and say I don't want that to happen I is
a local variable in the main function
and I don't want the set H function to
change it what I can do is add a cost
over here now I'm passing I as a Const
integer reference to the set H function
so if I compile the program now it will
fail
and if we remove the A+ pass it will
succeed so this is how a constant
reference is passed as a parameter to a
function Coast reference parameter is
widely used in suppressants functions
and you should be using it whenever it
is appropriate now consider if we remove
the reference and the set age function
only takes a constant integer as a
parameter in this case the Const is not
very useful it still means that a cannot
be changed inside the function but it is
not as useful as it is used as a
constant reference parameter because the
parameter is passed by value so in the
main function when I call set H I I'm
making a copy of I and pass that to the
function set H and whether the function
set age will use that copy as a Const or
non Const I don't care it's a copy
anyway do whatever you want so from the
colors point of view this Const is
useless if I overload this function with
another function that takes a integer as
parameter
the caller cannot differentiate these
two functions so if we compile it it
will fail and with the message that a
set age cannot be overloaded so from the
colors point these two function are the
same so these are the examples of Const
parameter and now let's look at an some
example of cost return value and here we
have a function get name which returns a
Const stream reference and the reason we
want to return accounts to stream
reference is the same reason why we want
a Const reference parameter we want to
return by reference to improve the
efficiency of the program and we want to
return a Const reference so that the
caller cannot change the value that the
variable that I returned and in the main
function I will use a Const string
reference n equal to t dot get name and
then print it out
the knee is printed out so this is how
use accounts the reference return value
now again let's consider remove the
reference and it returns accounts the
stream and now the cost is completely
useless because the name is returned by
value so what the function returned is a
copy of the name which is a temporary
and it doesn't make any sense for a
temporary to be defined as a constant
now let's consider a even more
interesting case Const function we have
a function called print dot name and
after the function signature there is a
constant but at this one this means this
function will not change any of the
member variables of this class so in the
main function we could call d dot print
dot name and let's do print something
different
cost can run it
and it prints out dummy cost however if
this function change then member
variables say age plus class and this
code doesn't compile and another thing
that you should remember is even if this
function doesn't change any of the
member valuables but it call another
function get name which is not a
constant function and this still doesn't
compile even though the get name
function doesn't change the member
variables at all so a Const function can
only call another constant function in
order to maintain the constant nests
another thing to note is the constant s
can be used to overload the function so
if we make a copy of this function and
remove the cost these two are different
functions and let's print out non
constant now the question is when this
function will be invoked and when this
function will be invoked the answer is
this function will be invoked when the
top is a Const and the dysfunction will
be invoked when the talk is not a cost
for example we have a talk d and the
desti should call the non constant
version of the print out name and say we
have another Const talk T 2 and then
call T 2 dot print dot name and this one
cannot be cat name you should change it
to name and now let's run it
so the first one is calling the nun
Const function print up name and the
second one is calling the Const function
print up name so this is how a Const
function can be overloaded with a
non-constant the last thing to note is a
function that takes a constant reference
parameter can also be overloaded with a
function that takes a reference
parameter the question is under what
circumstance this function will be
invoked and under water circle sometimes
this function will be invoked I'd like
to leave it as a homework for you to
figure out if you cannot figure out
watch my another video called
understanding L value and our value I'll
publish the answer if there are too many
people having trouble with it in summary
when the constant is used with the
function it can be used to specify cost
parameters or constitute term value or
Const function that's all for today feel
free to subscribe to my channel so when
I post a new video you'll be updated or
you can go to my channels home page and
see what I'm offering today bye bye