hello everyone last time we have talked
about using a chrome function to replace
copy constructor and copy assignment
operator so that object copying can only
have been explicitly today we'll talk
about another advantage of using chrome
function let's look at an example we
have a car stock and the yellow dog is
derived from dark in the main function
we have a yellow dot e and then we call
the function foo with the yellow double
D the function foo takes a dog's pointer
as parameter and the inside the function
we create a dog C which is copy
constructed from D do you see any
problem with this code we know that D is
a yellow duck so what the function foo
get is really a yellow duck but when you
a copy construct C we are copy
constructing a dog so as a result of
that D is a yellow dog and C is a dog
so see is not really at identical copy
of T this is not good because a copy is
a copy if it is not identical to its
original how can you call it a copy to
solve this problem we can use again a
clone function we define a public
virtual clone function and this function
will return a dog which is copy
constructed from itself and the yellow
dog also have a comb function but they
told it turn a yellow dog instead of
dark
and in the full function instead of
cutting the copy constructor directly
will call the clone function
and now see is indeed a yellow dock
so in a sense the chrome function is
like a virtual constructor it makes sure
the appropriate type of object will be
constructed no matter what kind of pipe
the original object has been casted into
one thing to note is this clone function
returns a tox pointer and that this
chrome function returns a yellow ducks
pointer even though one function is the
overridden function of the other this is
an important feature called covariant
return type it allows an overridden
virtual function in this case the clone
function to have a different return type
as long as its return type is derived
from the base class functions return
type so this is the important occipital
class language feature that makes the
virtual constructor possible thank you
for watching feel free to subscribe to
my channel and check out the other
videos I have see you next time