hello everyone in this session we'll
talk about preventing exceptions from
leaving destructors exceptions provides
a way for your program to react to
exceptional circumstances such as a
runtime error they do that by
transferring the control into a special
portion of the code called exception
handling
destructors like any other part of the
code they may flow exceptions however
you need to be very careful and that the
exceptions thrown by destructors are
contained inside of the disruptors they
should not be thrown out of the
destructor to understand why let's look
at some simple example we have a class
dog and dog has a constructor and a
destructor each one of them will print
out some message so we know they are
executed dog also have a method called
Park in the in the main function M we
create two dogs top one Henry of to Bob
and before Henry and Bob can bark a
little exception of 20 is thrown out the
exception of 20 will be caught by the
catch block now what will be the output
of this simple program
the output is Henry is born Henry is
born first because Henry's created first
then Bob is born Bob is destroyed why
Bob is destroyed first because Henry and
Bob are stored on stack stack is last in
first out because Bob is born last it
will be destroyed first and then Henry
is destroyed and tonday is caught the
main point that I want to make with this
example is before the exception of 20 is
caught by the catch block the stack will
unwind and all the local variables
inside the try block needs to be
destroyed so both Bob and Henry will be
destroyed before 20 is caught now having
that in mind that we remove the throw
statement now there will be no
exceptions in the main function
however I'll add a flow exception in the
dogs destructor
let's see what happens when an exception
is thrown out of a disrupter the result
is a disaster this program will crash so
what happened when the execution reach
the end of the try block so the stack
will unwind and all the local variables
needs to be destroyed so Bob will be
destroyed first when Bob's disrupter
executes it throws exception of plenty
as we've learned from previous
experiment before the exception of tante
is caught by the catch block Henry also
needs to be destroyed and Henry's
disrupter also s queued and also through
exception so as a result we'll have two
exceptions pending at at the same time
one plumb bob one plumb Henry and C++
doesn't like having work more than one
exception pending at at the same time so
it will just crash this is why we should
not flow exception out of a destructor
so what's our solution our solution
number one is the destructor swallow's
whatever the exceptions that it
generates in this example I put all the
exception prone code inside a try block
and catch the exception that I expect
you could also add another catch
statement with ellipsis
this will prevent any other unknown
exception from leaking out of the
destructor however you need to be very
careful about this kind of catch
statement because first of all it's not
very useful it doesn't give you any
error message and secondly sometimes
it's even dangerous because this kind of
statement will mask of any kind of
exception the downside of this solution
is since the exception is swollen by the
destructor the tops client will not get
the exception so they will not know what
has happened and to appropriate thing to
handle that this leads us to our second
solution which is move the exception
prone code to a different function not
in the destructor so the destructor will
contain code that is either exception
free or having very little chance of
throwing exception for example in our
docs example I'll remove the exception
thrown code in the destructor and add
another function called prepare to
destruct and in this function I'll do a
bunch of different things and it may
throw exceptions
now the destructor is exception free and
in the main function before dock one and
duck two gets destroyed they need to
call the prepare to destroy function now
first of all this program will no longer
crash and secondly the docks client will
get the exception and do a properly
thing to handle the exception the
downside of this solution is there o is
one additional API for docs client to
call so which solution should we use
solution number one destructor swallow
the exception or solution number two
move the exception prone code to a
different function the answer depends on
who is the better person to handle the
exception if it is a dog you saw
solution number one if it is dogs client
uses solution number two that's all for
today's session bye bye