hello everyone welcome back to C++
advanced today's topic is casting I
don't know about you guys but for me
casting has always been confusing topic
now exactly what is casting C++ is a
strongly typed language so an object can
convert it from one type to another
generally speaking and there are two
kind of type conversion one is implicit
type conversion another one is explicit
type conversion explicit type of
immersion is also called casting there
are full and for casting operator in C++
static cast dynamic cast Const cast and
lastly reinterpret cost let's start with
the study static cost so that your cost
can convert an object from one type to
another over here I define an integer I
equal to nine and then I cost i from an
integer to a float static cast can work
on any type of type as long as well as
the type conversion is defined for those
types here I create a string Bob and
then cast the string to a dog the
condition for this statement will work
is the type conversion is defined for
the conversion from string to dog
we've talked about the type conversion
in a previous session so I won't talk
about that here so that ticket cost can
also work on pointers or reference and
for point and reference and it can only
cast a objector from one type to a
related type a little later type that
means you can cast an about an object
from a base class down to a derived
class or cast it from a derived class up
to a base class in this example my
yellow dog is derived from dog and after
I create a yellow dog I can Custis a
pointer to a dog's pointer this is
static cast now let's look at dynamic
cast first I create a yellow dog and
then consider the pointer to a dog's
pointer now this is a static custom even
though I'm not using the study cost
operator then I Custer the docs pointer
PD back to yellow dogs pinpointer py
dynamic cast upon only work on pointers
or references it cannot work on an
object and they convert from one type to
a related type and typically it will be
used in ton cast which means it casts a
objective from its base class to a
derived class in the skins from talk to
a yellow talk another difference from
the static cast is the dynamic cast in
additional to performing the typecasting
it also perform a long time type check
it will check if the types are
compatible for the casting to succeed
in this case it will check if the PD is
pointing to a yellow dog a real yellow
dog and not just a dog and if the
casting succeed the py will become PD
and if it failed P Y or equal to zero
it's a null point and finally the
dynamic cast requires the two types to
be polymorphic which means they have
they need to at least have one virtual
function now let's look at the Const
caste constant caste is used to cast
away the constant is in the example I
have a constraint as pinpoints to hello
world and the hello world cannot be
modified because it defines to be a
constant then I can use constant cast to
custom way the constant is and then
assign the result to a mod for
modifiable child pointer and now the
hello world can be changed and like
dynamic casts that the constant cast can
only work on pointers or references it
cannot work on the object itself so if I
change this chart to a char pointer to a
char and it doesn't work that way and
unlike the dynamic cast the console cast
can only work on same type so both
string and modify above are both
charters the only difference is one is a
constant work and other one is not
constant
our last cast operator is a reinterpret
cast in this example I have a P pointer
which points to some edges and then I
will use reinterpret cast to interpret
the memory content in that edges into a
dog the reinterpret cast can also work
on an only work on pointers or
references it cannot work on the object
itself and if you compare to the
previous three cast that works on
pointers or references the static cast
is working on related type and the
dynamic cast also can work on related
type the Const past can only work on
same type and the reinterpret cast can
work on any type you can cast from one
pointer to any other type of pointer
with the reinterpret cast so this is the
most powerful cast and because it is so
powerful it also gives you a lot of room
to make mistakes that is why you always
need to use extra caution when using the
interpret custom typically new interpret
cast is used in low-level coding because
it tends to generate code that's not
potable
C++ also inherited that the
old-fashioned custom style from C let's
call it as C style casting and CC style
casting has to form one is the seen like
custom notation another is the function
functional notation in this example I
have a shot integer a and I cast it into
J I and J and the both format are the
same there is no difference between of a
syst I'll casting is really a mixture of
static cast Const cast and reinterpret
custom the only custard it doesn't
support it the dynamic cast so now we
have a seat style casting which just
does the exact same thing as 3 C++ style
cast then which one should I use
in general the Cystic plus plus style of
cast are preferred over the c style
the reasons are first of all it's easier
to identify in the code by grabbing an
underscore cast you can easily find out
all the secrets pressed style of casting
in your code
secondly the C++ style of cast tends to
generate less usage error that is
because there are four different type of
cast in C++ and each one have a narrow
lead to specify the purpose so that
gives you less room to make mistakes and
also C++ style just provide a long time
type check capability to check if the
types are compatible for casting so that
is also a powerful tool to use