hello everyone welcome back in last
session we've talked about the public
inheritance indicator is a relationship
between the base class and the derived
class
so the derived class should be able to
do everything the base class can do
although the derived class can do those
things in a different way it has to
offer some way to do these things to
maintain that is a relation
however in real-world programming
sometimes it is not so easy to maintain
the easier relation for example we have
a class bird and we have another class
penguin which is derived from bird and
we know a bird can fly so in the class
bird I can define a function called fly
and in some application code I can
create a penguin and penguin can invoke
the function fry because it's inherited
from bird now suddenly we are making the
penguin fly so what is wrong here we are
the victim of a imprecise language
English when we say bird can fly we are
not saying all birds can fly there are
certain birds that cannot fly like
penguin so the right way to do it is we
need to define a new class called the
flyable bird which is derived derived
from bird
and the fly function certainly should
belong to the flyable bird and now the
penguin is derived from bird and it
doesn't have to be able to fly so as you
sing and there are subtle things that
need to be taking taken care of to
maintain a is a relationship now let's
look at the second example we have a
cast dog and the dog can bark I'm just a
dog and a yellow dog is derived from dog
and it box I'm a yellow dog and in the
main function I create a yellow dog and
let it back and then I assign yellow
dogs pointer to a duck's pointer and
added a bug again the output of this
program is the dog first bug I'm a
yellow dog then it barked I'm just a dog
so the same dog calling the same
function resulted in different behavior
this is not good
now some people may say this is a
polymorphism you have a problem with
polymorphism a polymorphism means
different classes of objects react to
the same API will behave differently so
the key words there is different object
react to same API behave differently and
in this case we have the same object
react to the same API and is behave
differently so this is not polymorphism
this is n type polymorphism so as much
as we need a lawyer honest the dog we
need the object with consistent behavior
in C++ so the conclusion we get from
this example is never over never over
right non virtual functions if it as a
function that you really want to
override
make that function virtual let's look at
a different example we've learned the
lesson we'll only over light
virtual function so the dog has a
virtual function bug and the default
value for message is just a a yellow dog
derived on from dog and have a virtual
function bug with the default value of
message a yellow in the main function
I'm doing the exact same thing as
previous example I create a yellow dog
and let it bug and assign to a dog's
pointer and let it back again what's the
output of this program the output is
also exactly the same as before it will
first bug on my yellow dog and then bug
I'm just a bug so this is a cunning dog
indeed what is happening now we know
that virtual function is bound at long
time however the default value for
function parameter is bound at compile
time
so when PG box it will invoke the
virtual function of yellow dog as we
expected but it will pick up the default
value of a message from dogs park
function that is why the PG box I'm just
a dog so the lesson we can take from
this example is never override the
default parameter value for virtual
function now suppose we have the dog has
a different function bark which takes a
different primer parameter age and it
prints out I am
age yes Oh
now on the main function I will bark
with H 5 and let's remove the PD and
park
now when the py park with parameter 5
since yellow duck doesn't have a bug
function with the integer parameter it
should invoke the dogs bark with integer
right the answer is no this code won't
even compile the reason is when the
compiler see the bark function duel
first search P wise own class for a
function with the name buck in this case
it was search pop function inside the
yellow dog if the compiler cannot find
the a bark function it will continue
searching in dogs class however if the
compiler did find a park function inside
the yellow dog regardless of the
parameter and return value type it will
stop searching right there as a result
this bug function is the only bug
function that the compiler can see so
the two bug functions of dog are not
inherited by yellow dog
they are shadowed by yellow dots on park
function this is not good because the
easier relationship is broken the dog
can bark with the integer but the yellow
dog cannot park with the integer to
maintain the is a relationship one thing
we could do is and declare using dog
bark
this will again bring the dark spark
function back to yellow ducks scope and
the dis code will compile in summary to
maintain the is a relationship between
the base class and the derived class
there are four things that we need to
pay attention to number one precise
definition of the classes number two
don't override non virtual functions
number three don't override default
parameter values for virtual functions
last one false inheritance of a set of
the shadowed functions that's all for
today's session thank you for watching
bye bye