hello welcome to C++ advanced one of C++
is a critical feature is operator
overload it can exploit people's
intuition and reduce their learning
curve for new libraries assignment
operator is one of the operators that's
frequently being overloaded in this
session women don't talk about one
pitfall in implementing assignment
operator which is self assignment this
is the example of self assignment you
may ask where people really do stupid
things like this no they were not but
they may very well do things like this
and this is a self assignment when I and
J are equal that is why we need to
handle self-assignment appropriately in
our assignment operator now let's look
at our example we have a class dog and
dog wears colors so this dog has a data
member peak color which is a pointer to
a color class and the dog's assignment
operator will copy everything from the
right hand side out to itself and in our
case the main thing to copy over is the
P color the natural implementation of
that is I'll first delete my own key
color and then I copy constructor a P
new P color from the right hand side of
pahala
however there's a problem with this
implementation the problem arises when
this dog and right hand side dog are the
same dog in other words this is a self
assignment
if that is the case when I delete Pecola
I'm also deleting a pea color of the
right hand side dog then when I copy
constructor color from the right hand
side peak color I'm accessing an object
that is deleted and the result could be
disastrous so what's our solution one
simple solution is we can do a check if
this dog equal to the right hand side
dog then we simply return this now we
are in a much better situation the copy
that deleting angular copy constructing
only happens when this dog and run hands
a dog are not the same dog however
there's a stupid problem with this code
what happens if the copy constructor of
the right hand side dogs Pecola
clothes and exception in that case the
doc has deleted its own pee corner but
it failed to create a new P collar so
the dog ends up holding a pointer that's
pointing to an invalid object this is a
big problem if the docs client later on
wants to use the dog more and even
nobody is using the dog anymore when the
dog is destructed the docs destructor
may want to try to delete the pee color
again and that the result is undefined
so it seems what we really want to do is
delete pee color only after the new pee
color is created successfully and to
achieve that purpose I need to create a
copy of original key color
and then I create a new P color if that
is successful I'll delete the original P
color now we are safe even if the new
operator throws an exception the dog
still holding a pointer that points to a
valid color so this gives you a small
demo of writing exception safe code now
let's look at our solution to solution
to basically dedicates the assignment
operation to the color class so I simply
copy color equal to life I'm side P
color it will either do a member by
member copying of the color class or
invoke the color classes overloaded
assignment operator one thing to note is
I don't necessarily need to check if
this dog ended the right-hand side of
our the same dog if they are the same I
will make a copy of itself anyway
this may incur some one-time cost but
since it doesn't cause any serious
trouble I don't want to worry about the
wrong time cost now until later my
profile that helps me that this is
important besides the if statement is
not for free it will also incur some
runtime cost so be moving the if
statement will more or less compensate
the cost of the self assignment that's
all for today's class thank you for
watching bye bye