hello everyone welcome back today we are
going to talk about the three type of
inheritance public protected and private
inheritance what are they how should you
use them in your code in the example I
have a base class B and I have a class
deprived which is a private child of B D
plot protected a child of B the pub
public child of D of B the three
keywords private protected and public
specifies three different level of X
access control from the derived class to
the base class the access control rules
can be summarized into four rules number
one none of the derived class can access
anything that is private in B this
should be easy to understand because
these private members are B's privacy
and then no matter what kind of child
you are of B you cannot include B's
privacy secondly the pub inherits public
members of B as public and the protected
members of B as protected I assume you
have used the public inheritance a lot
of times in your code already so this
one should not be a surprise to you
either both B both these public and
protected members will become the pubs
type public and protected members third
one deprived which is a private child of
B inherits the public and protected
members of B as private in other words
both B's public and protected members
become deprived private members and
similarly and D plot which is a
protected a child of B inherits the
public protected members of B as
protected
in other words both these public and
protected members become departs pub and
protected a member now let's let's look
at the three kind of inheritance from
the custom points of view there are
three rules rules number one anyone can
cast a deeper pointer to a be pointer
because the pub inherits all the public
interface of B as a public interface in
other words the pub can do anything that
we can do so the pub is considered a
special kind of a B secondary the
privates members and the friends can
cast a deprived pointer to be pointer
and similarly a depressed member friends
and the children can cause that
depressed pointer into a beasts pointer
now it should be clear to you that only
public inheritance indicates a is a
relationship between the parent and
child neither of the private inheritance
and protected inheritance indicates a
easier relationship now let's look at a
live example our Class B has three
functions a public function of pub
protective function of plot and the
private function F Prime
now let's look at a deep pub the public
child of B inside the pub has a function
f F invoking bf pub function is okay
because f pub function has become D pubs
public function and similarly invoking
f-prot function is also okay because
it's now a D pubs protected a function
however invoking F Prive is not allowed
now let's look at the product the
protected the child of B the plot of F
function can invoke F pub also but the
reason is f pub has become deep rods
protected map function as compared to a
public function in the pub F plot also
has become deep lots protective function
and finally again it cannot access F
Prive now deprive class which is a
private member of a private child of be
deprived can access F pub and f-prot
because they has become a private
function of deprived as compared for a
protective function of D plot and the
deprived it also cannot access these
private function now in the main
function I created the D pub D 1 and
invoke F pub from D 1 which is okay
because F pub is D pubs public function
I create a D 2 and invoke F pub form D 2
which is error because F pub is D plots
protected function not public function
if I really want to invoke F pup
function from D to what I need to do is
inside the teapots definition I add a
using
be a pub this declaration will bring the
F pub function into the scope of deep
plot and then this error will go away
finally I can cast a D once point the
edges into a bees pointer P B but I
cannot custody two edges into a bees
pointer as we've talked the public
inheritance indicates a is a
relationship between the child and
parent the pub is a kind of B and then
what does the private inheritance mean
surprisingly private inheritance
indicate a relation that's similar to
composition in other words that has a
relation let's look at our example we
have a class ring and the ring
tinkles and for the composition our
class dog has a ring which is M ring and
when doc tinkles it invokes the green
stinker function this is commonly known
as call forwarding this demonstrates a
composition code structure however you
can do the same thing with private
inheritance now the dog is privately
derived from ring and the dog can bring
the rings thinker interface into the
docs interface with this statement
conversation and private inheritance are
similar in terms that both dogs can
access wins public interface and if
dog's client want to access those
interface the dogs have to bring those
interface into dock itself public
interface with either call forwarding or
with using declaration however they are
not totally saying the obvious thing is
that the private inheritance dog can
access rings protected members and this
guy cannot in general the composition
code structure is preferred over the
private inheritance because number one
composition is considered a better
object-oriented code structure since dog
dog can only access rings public
interface dog and a ring are more
decoupled and secondary and the
composition is more flexible for example
suppose and the dog wears two rings M
has another ring M R into with
composition it's easy to do that but
with private inherent inheritance it's
impossible and another example is
suppose the top is tied of the same ring
and during the runtime it once switched
a different ring and again it's easy to
for composition and hard for it's
impossible for private inheritance
there are a few rare case where the
private inheritance is actually
preferred over the composition for
example suppose the ring has a virtual
function chambo and the inside tinkle
and the virtual function is called and
in the dog we want to override that
tremble function so we can easily define
a virtual function chambo for dog and we
can reuse the tinkle function of a ring
if you want to do the same thing for
composition it's a lot more cumbersome
you have to create a new class
derived from ring and then override the
virtual function tremble and inside dog
you can have a member of the derived
ring in stuff instead of the original
ring overall the composition is still
the preferred code structure you should
always use composition whenever you can
and use private inheritance when you
have to this lets up our discussion on
the inheritance thank you for watching
bye bye