hello everyone today we will talk about
static initialization Fiasco problem
which is a subtle problem that can crash
your program we'll talk about how this
crash can be introduced and what's the
common solution to this problem let's
look at our example we have two classes
cat and dog let's first look at the
header file of the dog bulk has a
private the data member which is the
name of the dog and it also has a bark
function and a constructor that takes a
string as parameter the back function of
the dog prints out dog rules my name is
name and the constructor of the dog
brings out constructing dog and then
assign the name to the private the data
member of name the cat class is very
similar to the dog class except that
instead of having a back function it has
a mere function and that the print out
messages are slightly different it
prints out kettle's constructing cat in
the main function I create a global
variable D which is a dog with the name
of gunner and inside the main function I
call d dot Park let's run the program it
prints out constructing dog gunner dr.
rules
my name is gunner so far so good
now let's say I want to create another
global variable it's a cat see with the
name of smokey and inside the talks
constructor I'm going to call C dot meal
now we have two global variables one is
the cat C and another one is the top D
and since they are in different source
file the order of the initialization is
undefined in other words whether the D
will be constructed before C or C
constructed before D is undefined
this will cause a big problem because
when we construct D this constructor
will call C dot meal so at this point if
C is already constructed then we are
fine if C is not constructed then the
program will crash so in other words if
D is constructed after C then the
program will live if C is constructed
after D then the program will die so our
program has a 50 by 50 chance of dying
now let's run the program
aha this actually runs okay which means
the cat is constructed before the dog so
if we comment this out and in the cats
constructor we call e dot bark and we
also need to extern dog D because D is
defined in another source file now this
program should crash because we know
that the cat is constructed before the
dog
so when we call d dot park the talk D is
not constructed yet so this program
should crash let's run it
as you see the program crashed so how do
we solve this problem there are
different ways to solve this problem but
the most commonly used is the singleton
design pattern I have created another
class singleton and that the singleton
has a docks pointer PD a cat pointer PC
a destructor a get dark function and a
get cat function in the singleton source
file both PD and PC are initialized to 0
the get dock function will check if PD
is 0 if a PD is 0 it create a new dog
gulnur under loop 10 PD and next time
when that gets up function is called
wood it will not create a new dog it
will return the same dog PD this is
called initialize upon first usage EDM
the same thing for the cat the cat will
be initialized only when it needs to be
used now I don't need any global
variable of cat or dog whenever I need a
dog I call the get dog function and when
I need a cat I call the get cat function
and there will only be one dog of Ghana
and one cat of smokey available so in
the main function let's remove the
global variables and the let's say I'll
single term get cat Neil and in the cat
constructor let me move this and I'll
call single term get dark
bark and we don't need any global
valuable cat anymore
we should always call get cat when we
need a cat now let's run the program so
the program finished without a crash the
program should not crash because both
dog and cat will be created whenever
they are needed and note that the
singleton has a destructor if PD and PC
are not zero
they will be deleted and then we assign
them to zero so to make sure that both
the dog and cat will be deleted we only
need to create a singleton instance of s
when s goes out of scope it will
automatically delete either dog or the
cat or both
so both dog and cat will be constructed
and it deleted only if they are used if
they are not used nothing will happen
this is the beauty of singleton design
pattern that's all for today feel free
to subscribe to my channel and check out
the other videos I have bye-bye