hello everyone today's topic is
operating new and operated delete what
do they do and how to overload them
let's start with the basic I'm creating
a dog on the heap now exactly what would
happen as a result of this code there
are three things that would happen and
they have been in a fixed order step one
the operator knew this guy will be
called to allocate memory for dog
step two the dopplers constructor this
guy is called to create the dog step
three which is optional if step two dogs
constructor throws the exception call
the operator delete to free the memory
allocated in step one however if the
step one operate a new throw the
exception the operator delete will not
be invoked to free the memory because
the C++ will assume the allocation of
memory has not been successful so you
need to keep that in mind when you write
your own operator new delete PD will do
the opposite thing the docks destructor
is called to destruct dog and step to
operate the delete is cut to free the
memory this is a simplified version of
operator new that I use to demonstrate
what the standard operator new typically
does before going to the details
let me introduce new handler new handler
is a function that's invoked when the
operator new failed to allocate memory
by default a new handler is a null
pointer which means there's no new
handler but you can always set a new
handler with the set new handler
function
set new handler function not only
installs a new vendor it also returns
the old new handle or the current new
handler now let's look at the operator
new operate the new takes one parameter
which is the size of the memory to be
allocated and it it flows a bad air log
exceptions inside operator new there's
an infinite loop inside of the loop and
the first thing it does is to allocate a
memory of this size if the memory
allocation is successful then it returns
the memory and it's done mission
complete
if the memory allocation is not
successful and then it will fetch the
current new handler and check if the new
handle is now if it is not now invoke
the new handle function after that go
back to the loop and try to allocate the
memory again so you might you might have
guessed the purpose of the new handler
is to make more memory available so that
next run of memory allocation could be
successful if the handler is a null
pointer which means there's nothing I
can do to free the memory then it will
just throw a bad I log exception these
are the things that standard operating
you typically does you can overload the
operator new to do whatever things that
you want to do but it is generally a
good practice to follow the same format
of say the standard operate on you such
as a wire loop bad a log exceptions
you may have noticed that that here we
are defining a global operator new
sometimes you don't want to overload the
global or upload the new you only want
to overload the operator new for your
own class and here we are defining a
member operating new for our class dog
and the out member operating new also
takes the one parameter of size and also
throws up a dialog exceptions and inside
the operator new I call a function
customer new for dog which creates size
this size of the memory for dog now I
have a yellow dog which is derived from
dog and in the main function I created a
new yellow dog on the heap now do you
smell any problem from this code the
dogs operate the new is a public
function that means it will be inherited
by its child yellow duck so when I
create a yellow dog on the heap it will
actually call the dogs of revenue not
the standard operating you as a result
I'll be calling customer new for dog to
allocate a memory for yellow dog which
may or may not be what what I have in
mind
suppose I don't want that what can I do
creating a new yellow dog invokes the
dogs operating you however what
parameter will be positive to the dog's
operating you will be the dog size or
the yellow dollar size fortunately it's
the yellow dog size so inside the
operating new for dog I could do some
check based on that
if the size of the size is equal to dot
size
I'll call the customer new for dog
otherwise I'll call the standard
operating you for yellow duck
so this is one solution another solution
is since I've been defining a customized
and operate the new fourth dog maybe I
could I want to define a customized new
four yellow dog too so that's a second
solution now let's look at operator
delete an operator delete takes one
parameter width which is a pointer to
the memory to be deleted and it is not
supposed to throw any exception here
I've overloaded the operator delete for
dog and over later the operator delete
for yellow dog so the problem of the
previous example will not exist here in
the main function I create a new yellow
dog on the heap and assigns pointer to a
Doc's pointer PT and later I delete PD
do you see any problem with this code
when I delete PD which operator delete
will be invoked that's right it's the
Doc's operator elite will be involved so
I end up using the talks operator delete
to Tilke allocate the memory that's been
allocated for yellow dot which smells
trouble so what can I do you may
immediately suggest that making the
operator delete of virtual function
then the correct operated delete will be
invoked right this is certainly will not
work you cannot define a function to be
both virtual and Static because a
function being static specifies the
behavior of the class it has it is not
directly tied to the object and a
function being virtual specifies the
behavior of the object so static and
virtual belonged to different world that
is why it is forbidden insecure in C++
to define a function to be both virtual
and static then what's our solution if
you remember a previous session we've
talked about that if a class is meant to
be used polymorphically it should have a
virtual destructor that rules applies
here also we need to define a virtual
destructor for dog
even though the virtual destructor
doesn't do anything now when I delete PD
it will invoke the yellow ducks
destructor and magically invoke the
yellow dogs operated delete now let's
talk about why and when we want to
customize new and delete here I list
some of scenarios when you want to
customize new and delete but this is far
from a complete list first category is a
usage and a detection for example memory
leak if I keep in the operator new I
keep a record of all the memory being
allocated and the in the operator delete
I remove the memory from the record I
will have a list of the memory being and
leak and possibly I can also implement
my own garbage collection mechanism only
index over long and under on in the
operator new if I assign a special
signature to the first item of Nan array
and another signature to the last item
of the load array then I will be able to
detect array overall and under long
improve your vision see I could
clustering related objects to the same
place and to reduce page fault I could
use fixed size allocation which is good
for application with many small objects
I could use racket aligned similar sized
objects to the same place to reduce
memory fragmentation the third category
is performing additional tasks if my
program is dealing with high security
information it is a good idea to feel
that the allocated memory with zeros to
prevent those information to be leaked
to the outside world
lastly I could use the operator new to
collect the usage statics of the memory
for example what's the average size of
dynamically allocated memory what's the
biggest size of the memory how often the
memory allocation is performed etc the
last thing to keep in mind is it is easy
to write our operator knew and operated
delete that works but it is very hard to
write a good memory manager so before
you start off writing your own version
of new and delete you had there are two
alternative that you can consider number
one trick your compiler toward your
needs
read your compilers document carefully
and see if there is something you can
use that the compiler already provide
the second option is search the web for
memory management library there are many
good many memory management library out
there for example the poor library from
boost if the two alternatives doesn't
work for you then it's a time for you to
write your own version of the new and
delete all right
this wraps up our topic with the new and
delete bye bye and see you next time