hello everyone last time we've talked
about Caidic look up kenick look up is
for the purpose of function name search
it temporarily extend the scope of
function name search to the space where
the function parameter type is defined
so in this case it will extend the name
search scope for G to the space where X
is defined now it is really a good thing
for us doesn't that defeat the very
purpose of namespace and expose us to
the danger of name crash another thing
is if I have another function G which
also in a namespace and it doesn't take
parameter and then in main function I
call this function G this apparently
will not work so this call will succeed
and this call will fail and that they
are both under the same context and
calling a function from the same
namespace doesn't that look a little
weird it is a little weird if you are
not not used to viewing parameter as a
way of expanding the looking up scope
for function nevertheless Kinnick lookup
is a good thing to have and there are
two main reason behind that one is a
practical reason and another one is a
theoretical reason let me start with the
practical reason this is the code that
we use very often it prints out some
message to distend it out however the
reason this code can work is because of
kenick lookup although in the code we
only have one stood qualifier there are
two things in the code that comes from
the Stute namespace one is the sea out
another one is the left shifter
so if we don't have can look up we'll
end up having something like this this
is very ugly and what's worse is this
code won't even compile in order for it
to compile you have to do something like
this
this is even uglier than previous one so
having shown you the alternatives I
imagine you have started appreciating
Koenig look up can you look up make it
easier to mimic the behavior of operator
let's provided a bicycle path core
language therefore makes your code
cleaner now the theoretical reason let's
ask the question what is the interface
of class we have a namespace a and
inside a we have a Class C what is the
interface of C apparently all the public
functions that define inside a C are
part of the interface of C however if I
have another function called void H
which operate on C the function H belong
to in the face of C if you are
hesitating let me give you another one
the left shift operator that this guy
look like interface of C I would argue
both of them should be part of the
interface of C let's look at the
definition of a class a class describes
a set of data along with the functions
that operate on that data
so the definition didn't say along with
the member functions or that operate on
the data it only says functions so by
definition the function H and the left
shift operator are not excluded from the
class and if you really think about it
from Siskinds point of view there is no
fundamental difference between using
function f and function h in either case
they are using Class C and calling some
function that operates on Class C now
suppose I have another function J which
also operate on C but it is outside of
the namespace of a where you're called a
function part of C's interface
apparently not
J looks very much like a client function
that operates on Class C so with that
I'm introducing a important engineering
principle the principle says functions
that operate on Class C and in the same
namespace with C are part of C's
interface vice-versa functions that are
part of this interface should be in the
same namespace as C say I have defined
an object of see since the syntax says I
can invoke C's member function without
using a qualifier I should also be able
to invoke a non-member function that
operates on C without using a qualifier
if that function come from the same same
namespace as C because both functions
belong to the interface of C this is the
theoretical reason behind Kanak lookup
now suppose I am a little suspicious
about this principle what will happen if
I have a non-member function that should
belong to sis interface but not in the
same namespace as C will it bite me
let's look at example we have a
namespace a and inside a we have a Class
C then we define our operator path that
works on C this operator really should
belong to the interface of C but it is
not in the same namespace as seen in the
main function I create an array of C and
then call the standard library function
accumulate on the array and here is the
definition of the function accumulate
you can ignore most of the function
what's important to us is the cumulative
longs to name space stood and the
community function will invoke the
operator price since we've already
defined an operator price for see
apparently this is what we want to use
now the question is when the compiler
see the operator press can it find our
operator plus successfully the answer is
probably not it depends on what header
files that you have included remember
the name hiding law when the compiler
sees the operator plus it will first
search an operator plus in the current
scope and if it cannot find one it will
go to the global scope and search for it
however if the compiler did find an
operator plus in current scope
regardless of the types of parameter
that plus is taking it will stop
searching that is really bad because
there are a bunch of operator press
that's defined in the namespace student
and you could easily include some header
file and our own operator press is
hidden so you see this could indeed
fight me and the solution is follow the
principle and put that operator plus in
the same namespace as C now the compiler
will be able to see our operator press
because of the cane o'clock up this is
why we should remember the principle and
apply them during our daily coding thank
you for watching subscribe to my channel
so you will be updated when I post a new
video or you can go to my channels home
page and click on playlists to see other
videos that are more free bye bye