hello everyone today we will talk about
a sequence s keyword Const what else
comes to me Const is a compiled time
constraint that an object cannot be
modified so first it's a constraint that
a number an object cannot be modified
and secondly this constraint is enforced
at compile time so here I have a Const
integer I equal to nine and if I want to
change I to six and compile it filled
with the message assignment of read only
valuable I so this is what a constant
ask it enforces the constant is during
the compile time now let's look at some
more examples Const int star p1 what
does that mean it means the data that
point to 2 by P 1 is a Const but the cop
the point itself p1 is not constant
so if we do P 1 star equal to 5 and then
comment out this one and run it it will
not compile because the assignment of
read only location star P 1 however if
we do P 1 plus plus that modifies the P
1 itself and compile it it runs through
ok so P 1 is not a constant but the data
pointed to by P 1 is a constant the way
to remember it is by reading it Const
int so the integer is a constant next
example is integers star counts P 2 what
does this mean this is the opposite of
the P 1 which means the P 2 itself is a
constant but the data it points to is
not a constant
so the way to remember it is const p2 so
the p2 is a Const
next one is Const into star Const p3 now
both the point p3 and the data pointed
to by p3 are Const so it is easy to
remember Const int the integer is
constant constant e to p2 is constant
now here's the tricky one integer can
star p4 so what is constant what is not
constant the rule that you should
remember is this if Const is on the left
of a star data is the Const if Const is
on the right of the star pointer is the
constant actually you don't need to
remember all this all you need to
remember is if constant is on the left
of stop it's one thing and if Const is
on the right of star it's another so in
this case we can rewrite this code
by changing the order of hint and
constant and think since in both case
the constant is on the left of the star
so there are the same and this one is
much easier to make sense of its
constant that integer is constant so for
this case the data is constant is not in
C++ that type of data can be casted from
one to another and the constant use of a
data can also be casted away let's
comment out all this and go to the first
example we know this will not compile
because we are change changing a
constant data say I really really want
to change the integer I what I can do is
this
Const cast integer ref I equal to 6 and
now let let's compile it
a glance through okay so the const cast
can cast away the countenance of I now
say I have a integer J and J is not a
constant so I can change it to any value
I want but at a certain point I want to
make J account what I can do is use
static cast Const integer left J this
will make J a constant integer and if I
modify its value to 7 and compile it
field and the message is assignment of
read only location comes to individual J
so with cost I can cast away that cut
constant is over data and I also can
cast a data into account but in general
cost is not a good thing you should
avoid them as much as possible by cast
away the confidence of a data I'm
breaking someone's promise for that data
to be a constant so cost is a hacky way
of coding
so what's the benefit of using constant
the beginners usually don't like Const
it looks like nothing but the
troublemaker when the code doesn't
compile remove the Const and the
compound
however Const is really a good thing to
use it has several benefits first of all
Const guards against in the divergent
right to a variable so it can stop the
wrong behavior at the compile time
rather than wait until the long time
secondly Const is a way of self
documenting by using Const you are
telling your reader that this variable
will not be changed and that is a extra
information for your readers to
understand the code number three comes
in DuBose the compiler to do up more
optimization so the compiler can make
the code tighter and therefore faster
and lastly Const also means that the
variable can be put in ROM the read-only
memory this is particularly useful in
the embedded programming so as a
professional C++ programmer you should
be using Const Pro actively next time
we'll talk more about constant
that's all for today feel free to
subscribe to my channel so when I post a
new video you'll be updated or you can
go to my channels homepage and see what
I'm offering today bye bye