hello everyone today we are going to
talk about static polymorphism when we
talk about polymorphism by default we
are talking about dynamic polymorphism
because dynamic polymorphism is such an
important part of object-oriented
programming and here I'm giving you an
example of dynamic polymorphism this is
an example of tree passing we have a
class generic parser and the generic
parser has a member function past
pre-order which does the pre-order
passing of the tree and the while
passing the tree it invoke a function
process node which it has certain
specific thing to this particular node
however the genetic parses process node
function is an empty function which does
nothing the employee child process
parser is a specialized parser and it's
derived from the generic passer it
overrides the process node function and
it does some customized thing for the
employee chart in the main function that
employee chart parser is created and
that the employee chart parser will call
the pass pre-order function from its
base class the pass pre-order function
will call process node because the
process node function is a virtual
function so it will actually call the
employee child process process node so
the generic algorithm of pass pre-order
is customized by the employee child
passes own process node function this is
a typical example of polymorphism we
like polymorphism because it makes your
code more clean and elegant it helps you
to write more generic code that is more
decoupled from other code
however polymorphism is not for free it
comes with a small price to pay the
price is number one the memory cost of
the virtual table and number two the
runtime cost of dynamic binding which is
basically the code that creates and uses
the virtual table this costs us more
however what if my profiler tells me
that this is a critical part of my
algorithm and it needs to run as fast as
it can and I don't want to give up on
the benefit of polymorphism what can I
do one solution that I'm going to show
you in this video is we can actually
simulate the behavior of polymorphism
and by simulating it we are getting its
benefit and not paying in surprise
before going to the solution let's take
a look what are the things that we want
to simulate first is a relationship
between the base class under the derived
class so the employee chart parser is
publicly derived from the generic
passive class number to base class
defines a generic algorithm that is used
by the derived class in this case the
generic algorithm is the past pre-order
function number three the generic
algorithm is customized by the derived
class in this example that is done with
the process node function
having these three things in mind let's
look at our solution this is our
solution the first thing you might
notice is the base class generic path so
now has become a temporary class of type
T past pre-order function is the same as
before however the process note function
is changed instead of doing nothing like
before it will statically cast this
object into the type of T and invoke the
process note function of the type T now
here's the tricky part the employee
chart passer is publicly derived from
generic passer and the generic passer is
a temporary class with a template type
of employee chart passer
think about it the rest of the code is
the same the process node will do some
customized thing for the employee chart
and in the main function is also the
same will create an employee chart
processor and invoke the pass pre-order
function for the inquiry chart the pass
pre-order function is a function of the
generic passer over here it will invoke
the process node function please note
that the process node function is no
longer a virtual function so the generic
passer will call itself the process node
function not the employee child passes
process node function however the
generic process process node function
will cast this object into type of T and
invoke this process node function in
this example the type T is actually
employee child processor
so eventually it is the employee chart
processes process note function that's
got invoked thus the polymorphism is
achieved now let's review the three
elements that we want to simulate there
is a relationship between the base class
and the derived class that is still true
this class defines a generic algorithm
that is used by derived class which is
also true the generic algorithm is
customized by the derived class and here
is done by the process node it's also
true so we are getting all the benefits
of polymorphism but we are not paying
any price for it another thing to note
is from our kind point of view they can
use our class as if it is a true
polymorphism they don't even care
whether it's real or simulated
polymorphism this technique is called
curiously recurring temperate it is also
called static polymorphism or simulated
polymorphism it is very fairly popular
in the library code because in most of
the application code you don't really
care about the cost of the virtual table
and the dynamic binding unless the your
profiler tells you that this is
important but in the library code often
time you want to squeeze every bit of
performance out of your code so we are
getting all the benefits of polymorphism
but we are not paying in price for it
it's like free lunch right
now nothing is free in this world
everything comes in with the price
except my video which is totally free so
what is the price we are paying here
suppose I create another parser which is
cut military chart parser and that the
military child parser will be derived
from the generic parser of the time rate
type of military child parser note the
generic part genetic parts of employed
child parser and the generic parts of
military child processor are two
different classes they're distinguished
classes that occupies their own space in
the program image now you would realize
that the launch is not free this is a
typical trade-off between a program
image size and program performance
whether the trade-off is worth it it
totally depends on your application
another thing I want to point out is
this is also a small demo of TMP
template meta programming the idea of
temporary meta programming is it moves
part of the computation which typically
happens during a long time up front to
the compile time therefore improve the
efficiency of your program
and that is exactly our static
polymorphism does although static
polymorphism only improves the
efficiency a little bit some time by
using the TMP technique you can make
much bigger improvements to your program
the last thing that I want to point it
out is when some people talk about
static polymorphism they are actually
referring to the template itself in this
example I have a temperate function max
which goes through every element of the
vector V and find the largest one and
return it and when function max is
materialized with any different type of
T or the operators such as large then
and copy assignment will be invoked with
different version of the operator large
then and copy assignment and because
that happens in the compiler time they
call it static polymorphism there's
nothing wrong with it it's just a
different definition I just want to
clear up with the concepts so next time
you hear other people talking about
static polymorphism you know which one
they are talking about that's all for
today thank you for watching bye bye