hello everyone today we are going to
talk about multiple inheritance multiple
inheritance is where a class is directly
derived from more than one base classes
people have different opinions with the
multiple inheritance some people says if
single inheritance is good then multiple
inheritance must be better and some
people say multiple inheritance brings
too much troubles and Saturdays and it
the benefits is simply not worth the
trouble in today's video I'm going to
show you all the benefits and Saturdays
with multiple inheritance and in the end
I'll lay out my position on this and you
decide for your own position let's look
at an example we have a class input file
which opens a file to read so it has a
public read function we have an output
file class and open the file to write
and of course it has a write function
and later on it turns out I need to open
a file for both reading and writing and
then it makes sense that we create
another class called IO file which
inherits both input file and output file
and as a result the IO file can do both
reading and writing so far so good
multiple inheritance has served its
purpose now in order to read a file we
must open the file first so the input
file needs another function called open
and for the same reason the output file
also needs a function open
now in the main function I create an i/o
file F and I call F dot open this code
will not compile because the i/o file
has two instance of the open function
one open is inherited from input file
and another open is inherited from the
output file so the compiler will issue
error saying I don't know which open you
want to call and what's even worse is if
the input file has a private open
function now the i/o file has access to
only one function of open so the F dot
open should invoke the output files open
function right now this code still will
not compile the C++ standard says before
the compiler sees accessibility of a
function it must decide which function
is the best match for the function call
so before the compiler see that this
hope this open function is private it
must first determine which open function
should be invoked that is why the
compiler will still issue error saying
ambiguous code to the open function to
open the file successfully you have to
say F dot output file comma comma open
that will specifically tell the compiler
that you want to use the output files
open function to open the file now you
have seen one Saturday with the multiple
inheritance and let's see more
since both input file and output file
have the open function it makes sense
for the input file and up file to have a
common base class and move the open
function to that common base cast and
that is what we are going to do we have
a file class and that the file have a
name of string and also the open
function and both input file and output
file are derived from file an i/o file
is derived from both input and output
file now in the main function if I call
the i/o files open function it should be
okay right because we only have one open
function available and says no the
compiler will still issue an error
saying and the quiz code to open the
reason is the input file will inherit an
instance of of open function and that
the output file also inherited an
instance of the open function so the i/o
file still ends up having two instance
of open function one from the input file
one from the output file
that is why the compiler will issue our
errors in ambiguous caught with the open
function this is a commonly known as a
diamond shade problem because the
classes forms a diamond shape of
hierarchy the i/o file not only has two
instances of open function it also has
two instances of name and I can assign
different value to the two names for
example I can do F dot input file comma
comma name equal to Phi o 1 and F dot
output file
comma comma name equal to file 2 so this
is a problem why do we need two instance
of open and two instance of name how to
fix this c++ provides a solution called
virtual inheritance i can virtually
inherit the input file from the file and
the virtually inherit output file from
file what that means is we are telling
the compiler will only need one instance
of name and one instance of open
function during the process of
inheritance and as a result these two
lines of code will not compile under the
F dot open will compile successfully
okay the virtual base class is good it
solves our problem however it introduces
another problem it's a problem about
initialization suppose we have defined a
constructor for file which takes a
string parameter of filename since we
have defined a non-default constructor
for file the compiler will not generate
a default constructor for us which means
all the files children have to
explicitly initialize the file in their
constructors and the i/o file will
initialize both output file and input
file this will work out okay if it is a
single inheritance when I create a I or
file f io file we will initialize the
output file which in turns initialize a
file however this is a problem for
multiple inheritance when IO file is
derived from both input file and the
output file it needs to initialize both
input file and output file which in
turns initialize two instance of file
that is bad and C++ provides a solution
by defining a rule the rule states that
the initialization of the based virtual
class is the responsibility of the most
derived class in our case the most
derived class is the IO file so IO file
in addition to initializing its direct
parents it also needs to initialize the
based virtual class file and these two
instance of initialization are simply
ignored this is the kind of awkward and
non-intuitive but we have to live with
it if we will want to use multiple
inheritance and this rule applies no
matter how far the IO file is from the
file in the hierarchy as long as the IO
file is the most derived class it always
bears the responsibility of initializing
the virtual base class so if the
multiple inheritance is so difficult to
use why do we have to use it the answer
to that is interface segregation
principle the interface segregation
principle states that if an interface is
too large then split the interface into
smaller and most specific ones so that
the kinds will only need to know about
the methods that are of interest to them
say I want to write a program to model a
person called nd nd is a very
complicated person he can do a lot of
things you can provide a lot of services
so to completely model nd I might end up
having a class that has 500 api's this
will make nd a very difficult person to
deal with
he has 500 api's how am I supposed to
talk to him it turns out it doesn't have
to be that difficult nd is also an
engineer the engineer class provide all
the services that the engineer can
provide which is a much smaller number
of API say 40 API
now ng is an engineer so we can publicly
derived from engineer and I'm a
co-worker for nd so in order to have a
happy time co-working with nd I only
need to know about Andy's engineer api's
I don't necessarily need to know about
any other things that nd does in other
words I only want to instantiate nd as
an engineer and talk to him through his
engineer interface however from Andy's
parents point of view Andy is also a son
and they want to instantiate Andy as a
son and talk to him through his sons
interface which is let's say 50 api's
and Andy is also derived from some class
and this list can go on and on as nd
place different role in his life so as
you see by applying interface
segregation principle we are making nd a
much easier person to deal with because
each end is client only have a smaller
and the most specific interface to know
about in order to talk to nd so you know
daily programming if you end up having a
class that has a large number of AP is
and that the class is servicing
different group of clients maybe it is
time for you to use interface
segregation principle and when using
interface segregation principle the
multiple inheritance has a essential
essential role to play now you
understand the importance of multiple
inheritance the question is how can we
use multiple inheritance without getting
into all the troubles that we talked
about
in previous examples to answer that
question that may introduce a new
concept it's called pure abject class
C++ standard provides the concept of
abstract class an abstract class is a
class that has one or more pure virtual
functions a pure abstract class is a
class that contains only pure virtual
functions it has no data it has no
concrete functions and here is an
example of pure abstract classes in a
nutshell a pure fz8 class is a class
that has no implementation it only
provides interface and provides zero
implementation and it turns out all the
problems that we've talked about
duplication of data duplication of the
functions the initialization problems
all the problems will be gone if we only
derive from pure object classes if all
the base classes will put file our
profile and file are pure abstract
classes that has no implementation then
there is no such problem as duplicated
implementation and initialization
because there is nothing to duplicate
and nothing to initialize anyway and we
don't even need the virtual inheritance
anymore
so all the problems are gone but we
still have the benefits of interface
interface segregation principle
because the interface segregation
principle cares nothing about the
implementation it only cares about the
interface it will work out perfectly
fine if engineer and the Sun are pure
abject classes summary number one
multiple inheritance is an important
technique to have one example of it is
the interface segregation principle
number two if you are using multiple
inheritance it is strongly recommended
that you only derive from pure object
classes that's all for today thank you
for watching bye bye