hello everyone today we are going to
talk about the duality of public
inheritance the seemingly innocent
public inheritance actually has a
duality in it which is the inheritance
of interphase and that the inheritance
of implementation a public inheritance
could be either one of them or both of
them let's look at our example our caste
dog has a bark function and the buck
function is a pure virtual function and
the yellow dog which is derived from dog
overrides the buck function with its own
implementation now in this case the
yellow dog inherits the interface of the
buck function and does not inherit the
implementation of the bark function
because the bug function doesn't have an
implementation anyway it's a pure
virtual so this is a interface only
inheritance now suppose we have another
function it's a regular function called
one and of course the run function needs
a implementation
as we discussed in the other video of
maintaining is a relationship a
non-virtual function should not be
overridden so the yellow duck should not
over light that run function as a result
the yellow duck will inherit the
interface of the wrong function as well
as the implementation of the run
function so this is a doer inheritance
of both interface and implementation now
let's have another virtual function
called eat and this virtual function has
its own implementation
now the yellow dog is given a choice
it can either override the eat function
or not override it if they choose not to
override the eat function then it is
just like lon
the yellow dog will inherit its
interface as well as its implementation
if the yellow dog choose to override the
eat function then it is just like bark
the yellow dog will inherit its
interface but not implementation instead
it will provide its own version of the
implementation so you can say a non pure
virtual function is providing a
inheritance of the interface as well as
a default implementation now let's have
another function it's a protected
function called the sleep and it has its
own implementation
since the function is protected the
yellow dog will inherit the function
however it only inherits the
implementation of the function and not
the interface of the function to provide
a service for sleep the yellow dog need
to provide its own version of the public
function let's call it void I sleep and
this function will call sleep
now the yellow dog has its own interface
for sleep so as you see a protective
function provides a implementation
inheritance only to summarize the types
of inheritance provided by a C++
language there are four types type 1 a
pure virtual public function inherits
interface only tab to a non virtual
public function will Herot both
interface and implementation type 3 in
pure virtual public function will hear
its interface and a default
implementation type for a protected
function inherits implementation only as
a software designer who is designing the
software it is very important to
separate the concepts of interface and
implementation because he needs to know
when to use interface inheritance and
when to use implementation inheritance
now the question for us is when
interface inheritance is the main
feature of inheritance the purpose of it
is number one subtitle which means one
type can be safely used in the context
where another type is expected number
two polymorphism as you see these two a
very important technique in
object-oriented programming and they are
closely related so a pure virtual
function which is interface inheritance
only should be widely used when a
subtyping and polymorphism is needed
pitfalls of interfacing habitants be
careful of interface bloat since the
interface of a parent class is inherited
by its child class it can easily lead to
interface plot interface should be
designed to be minimally enough it
provides enough functionalities but the
size of it should be minimal another one
is interface should not reveal
implementation details the whole purpose
of interface design is to hide the
implementation details so the
implementation can change as much as it
like the interface should stay
relatively fixed if I interface reviews
the implementation details then we are
losing all the benefits of a projection
what about implementation inheritance
implementation inheritance is generally
not encouraged although some time we do
need them implementation inheritance has
many problems one for the biggest
problem is it increases code complexity
think about the way we write code we
first load a chunk of code into our head
understand it get things right and then
move on and load another chunk the
problem with implementation inheritance
is it makes that chunk of code too big
for our head
in order to get something right in the
derived class I have to have a good
understanding of all its base classes
and in order to change something in the
base class I have to be very careful not
to break anything in all its derived
classes so things becomes complicated
non virtual functions and impure virtual
functions inherits both interface and
implementation however the
implementation inheritance should be
considered as side benefit of the
interface inheritance a protected
function will Hertz implementation only
so it should not be encouraged in
general if there's some implementation
needs to be shared by the base class and
derived class move that implementation
to some helper class and both base class
and derived class shall have access to
that helper class it is much more
flexible that way guidelines for
implementation inheritance number 1 do
not use intelligence for code reuse use
composition instead inheritance is not
for code reuse compensation is number to
minimize the implementation in base
classes base classes should be seen with
implementation number 3 minimize the
level of hierarchies in implementation
inheritance so both number 2 and the
number 3 will reduce the number of
implementation inheritance
some people claim that inheritance is
evil and it should be avoided altogether
I'm not convinced of that but I do agree
the second statement inheritance is
often useful but more often overused or
I should say abused this is particularly
true for implementation inheritance when
implementation inheritance is used too
much it does make inheritance look like
evil but in the end inheritance is just
a tool for you to use and like any other
tools when it is used inappropriately it
will hurt you however one cannot call a
knife evil because it is used in your
proprietary and cut your finger if you
can remember all the pitfalls and
guidelines the inheritance in your code
should not look like evil that's all for
today's topic the duality of public
inheritance interface and implementation
see you next time