hello everyone last time we have
discussed Const function accounts the
function is a member function that
doesn't change member variables so if a
function that changed member variables
it cannot be a cost function today let's
stay back and rethink the question what
does it really mean for a function to be
cost for example we have a class big
array and the big array has a member
variable V which is a huge vector of int
big array also has another member
variable access counter which keeps
track of how many times V has been
accessed there is also a function get
item which takes a parameter of index it
incremented the access counter and then
we turn an item of V at the position of
index from my programming models point
of view this function get item really
should be a constant function because
the vector V is the primary data that
I'm concerned with the function get item
did not change any value in V it only
take a peek at the item at a position of
index so the function get item really
should be a constant this is my logic
constant list of what accounts function
mean however if I compile this program
the compiler reports an error saying
increment of member access counter in a
read-only object so the compiler
disagree with me that this function get
item can be a Const function because I'm
changing one one of the member variables
of access counter so the compiler
maintains the concept of bitwise
constant is as long as the function has
made change to the member variables it
cannot be a constant function so there
is a conflict between my model of logic
constants and the simplest process
concept of bitwise Council Ernest how
can we solve this conflict the solution
is we can make the member of access
counter a mutable member by making it a
mute book member this variable can be
changed in a Const function so if we run
this program again now it can run
through successfully
just for the fun of it even if tsipras
pants doesn't have the support of
mutable members we still have a solution
we could use Const cast to cast away the
constant is of this object and then
increment the access counter and this
let's run it it also runs through okay
however as I said cust is a hacky way of
coding and you should use it only when
you have to now let's consider another
example say big array has another member
called V 2 and V 2 is another big
integer array and it also has another
member function called set V 2 item and
this apparently is not a constant
function it is setting the value of V 2
it sets the item of V 2 at the position
of index to be X however if we change
this function to be a constant function
and run it it is still run through ok
so even though in my programming model
this is not a constant function the
Sigma's passed compiler will happily
accept it as a Const function because
this function has maintained the bitwise
constant Ness of this class it doesn't
change any of the members directory so
this is another example of conflict
between logic constants and the bitwise
constants
however this conflict is easy to solve
all we need to do is remove the Const
and now this function is not a constant
function anymore
as a summary during the software design
if the logic constant is is what you are
striving for then you should use mutable
members to implement the logic consulars
this wraps up our discussion about Const
lastly let's have a quiz here is a
declaration of function fun and it has
Const integer pointer Const fun Const
integer pointer Const ref P constant
what the heck is this
you can post your answer below as a
comment and the see if you can get
everything correct good luck that's all
for today
feel free to subscribe to my channel so
when I post a new video you'll be
updated or you can go to my channels
home page and see what I'm offering
today bye bye