hello welcome back in last session we've
covered a different type of casting in
C++ in this session we'll look at some
examples and come up with the summary
let's look at the example with dynamic
cast we have a dog which has a virtual
destructor remember the dynamic constant
requires the types to be polymorphic so
they need to have at least one virtual
function and we have a yellow dog
derived from dark and the yellow dog can
bark in main function I first create a
new dog and assign it to a dog's pointer
PD and sometime later under different
context I got a wrong impression that
the PD is actually pointing to a yellow
dog so I dynamically cast PD to a yellow
ducks pointer P Y which is obviously a
bug that I introduced then I let py part
and for debug purpose I print out the
value of py and PD now what will be the
output from this program you may want to
pause the video and think about it
the output is wolf it barked and the py
is e 0 and PD is some kind of pointer so
what happened in this code first of all
yellow dog is derived from talk so that
means all yellow dogs are talks but not
all dogs are yellow dots so when I
Custer a PD and which is a dog - a
yellow dog it's certainly will fail and
as a result the py will become 0
as we seen here and then when py back
isn't that a now access it's actually
not because when the compiler cpy to bug
it will try to interpret back function
to be a static function and in this
example the Park function didn't access
any member of any data member of a
yellow dog so it can indeed be treated
as a static function so py pocket is
successfully which makes a perfect cover
for my bug
now suppose I make the Park function to
access the yellow dogs member data
now the compiler can no longer treat bug
function as a state function
so when pew our box it will crash which
is a better thing because the the
debugger will immediately pointing me to
where the bug happened rather rather
than before the bug is completely hidden
and I have no idea when the bucket will
explode now suppose I am NOT going to
use dynamic cast I use static cast
unlike dynamic cast the static cast will
not perform runtime type check so the
static cast off I yell a Doc's pointer
to a yellow ducks pointer will always
succeed so py can will never be a null
pointer when py bug it will access a
part of memory that it doesn't belong to
py and that the result is undefined
sometime it will crash but most of the
time it will run through and print out
of print out atom number for H so as a
result the bug become more in changed
and elusive this is why we need to be
very careful when using cast and
apparently static cast is a more risky
to use then dynamic custom the correct
way to do it is we still use dynamic
custom and before let me py to park will
check if py is null pointer or not
and now it will work as we expected but
can we make the code better we actually
can a better approach for this code is
adding a virtual bulk function for dog
and now in the main function instead of
using a dynamic cast with some type know
check I can simply call py back now why
this code is better first of all it
reduced the cyclomatic complexity of the
code instead of having three lines of
code with a if statement I have only one
line of code and secondary and this is a
better object-oriented design because
we're relegating the responsible
responsibility of invoking the
write-back function to the object itself
a PD whether it's a dog or yellow dog so
we'll have a better manage to code and
lastly by using the virtual function I
can gain a little bit of the performance
advantage because the dynamic cast using
long time type identification and long
time type identification could be very
costly for a depending on the compiler
and sometime it could be up to 50 50
times more expensive
so in summary polymorphism is a better
and more elegant solution and then using
typecasting sometimes the casting can
become a handy tool to hack code which
may or may not be a good thing but we'll
look at it anyway again we have a class
dog and dog have bark function and this
time the bug function is a constant
function what does the account function
mean who is Const literally speaking
only a variable or an object can be a
Const a function cannot be a constant
then who has become Const as a result of
the keyword Const it's it's the object
pointed to by this pointer become Const
in the scope of the buff function now if
in the bug function I try to change you
and name equal to Henry the compiler
will not let me to do it because the
compiler knows that function is a cost
function and I cannot change the member
data of the dog in this function however
if I really want to change the name of
the dog in this function I can do host
cost
DOX pointer this and named equal to
Henley now I have successfully changed
the data member of dog inside the dog's
constant function this is a table that
summarizes all the castings that we've
talked about so far and there are a lot
of information in this table so I hope I
will not put you into sleep first of all
I grouped all the casting into two
groups
why is object casting and another one is
pointer and reference cutting because
these two are so much different from
each other in terms of the behavior
there are four columns first ones
generate code it indicates whether the
casting will generate a substantial
vulnerable code that will get executed
during one time generate data whether
the casting will generate a different
data object and saved in memory here I
don't count a pointer as a data only the
pointy counts risky level how risky is
it to use the cast they type what kind
of data type can the cast perform Oh
object casting there are only one cast
can be used on object casting which is
the static cast now the static cast for
object always generate code it will
invoke either the type conversion
function or the constructor of the
casted are type so it will generate a
substantial runnable code generate data
the static cast of object will generate
a new data and to be used risky level
static instead of object is not so risky
to use the only place I can think of is
if you defined too many of the implicit
type conversion then sometimes the code
will become tricky data type you can
perform static cast on any types as long
as the type conversion is defined for
these two types pointer reference
casting all forecasts can be used on a
point and reference casting static cast
the for pointers it will not generate
code at merely to tell the compiler to
interpret the pointer in a different way
it will not generate data either it will
work on the same data that's being
pointed to and as we've seen in previous
example that static cast is very risky
to use it always succeed and and you
need to be very careful not to make a
wrong cast
static a stall can only work on related
types which means between child and
parent dynamic cast will generate
additional vulnerable code because it
will perform long time type check to see
if the type two types are compatible for
dynamic custom dynamic cast typically
will not generate additional data it
will work on the same data being pointed
to and the dynamic cast is less risky
than the static cast because of the
dynamic runtime check it performs and it
can only work on related types and most
of them it's used for time casting down
casting Const cast will not generate
code and will not generate data and it's
very safe to use but it's not completely
risk-free because by using Const cast
you are changing an object that original
being consider the Const so you are
breaking someone's promise for the
object to be cost tons Const cast can
only work on same type reinterpret cast
it will not generate a code it will not
generate data and it is the most risky
operation you can do it can work on any
types and it will always succeed which
means you need to be very clear what you
are doing and making sure you are
casting things correctly
sISTAR Casta is a mixture of a static
cast Const cast and a reinterpret cast
so based on that you can get the answers
for the table based on the content of
previous table I've uploaded out the
notes to my personal website and you can
download notes and save it for future
reference if you like so this wraps up
our discussion on the castings I hope
you enjoy the video see you next time
bye