hello everyone welcome to C++ advanced
today we are going to talk about our
value and our value our value and our
value are not something that you learn
into very often some people has
programmed the C++ for years and they
still don't have a good understanding of
what our value and our values are so the
question to ask is why do I care our
value and L value are actually two very
important concept in C++ core language
having a good knowledge of them will
help you understand C++ construct and to
explain some similar strange behavior of
C++ it also can help you to decipher
compiler errors and warnings because
these two terms appears quite often in
the compiler messages a second reason
that you should care about them is C++
11 introduced a new feature called our
value reference if you don't have a good
grasp of our value and our value it will
be impossible for you to learn our value
reference so what are the error values
and our values it is hard to give a
rigorous definition of what they are so
instead here I'm giving you a simplified
definition which is generally accepted
and it should serve you well in 99% of
the time l value is an object that
occupies some identifiable location in
memory so the key word here is it's
something in memory not something in the
register and secondly it is it has
identifiable address
our value is defined by exclusion any
object that is not a L value it's our
value now let's look at some L value
examples I have an integer
I I is a L value Y it is our L value
because I can get its address with am %
and assign the edges to a integer
pointer so it's edges it not only has a
address and it's address is identifiable
and that the content of that edges can
be modified by assigning I to a
different valuable second example is I
have a class dog and then I will create
a dog D 1 and D 1 is a l value of a
user-defined the type a class it is fair
to say that most of the variables in C++
code are l values now let's look at some
other value examples I have integer X
equal to 2 as we said X is a l value and
the 2 is our value X equal to I plus 2 I
plus 2 is our value why are they our
values because if I try to get their
edges like this the compiler will error
out and I also cannot assign a different
value to them so there are values
another example I have a dog D 1 and D 1
equal to talk and dog is our value of
user defined type class now let's look
at function I have a function sum which
takes an integer x and y and return the
sum of X Y and then I have I equal to
sum 3 for some 3/4 is the r-value how in
summary what are the are values in these
examples two is our value I plus two is
I value dog and the Sun and also X plus
y is also our value and what are the L
values X hi
t1 that's it
oh I have another one P now let's look
at reference I assume you are already
familiar with the reference in C++ here
I create an integer I and initialize the
integer reference are with I this
reference is actually should be called L
value reference because R is a reference
to our L value I
and if I initialize the reference our
ways are value of five then the compiler
will error out and the only exception
for this is if R is a constant reference
then it can be assigned with five
although you should you really should
consider this is a shortcut of two step
operation step one our L value is
created with five and step number two
the reference R is initialized with this
temporary l value now let's look at the
same idea with the function I have a
function Square which takes l value
reference X and returns X square when I
invoke the function square I I is the
integer and it is okay if I invoke the
function square for T then it is an
error because for T is not a l value
it's an R value how can I make the
fungus function square for T work the
workaround is I can change the parameter
of the square function into a Const
integer reference and as we've seen in
previous example a Const individual
reference can be initialized with our
value so the square for T will work and
the square I still will work
what confuses most of the people in the
transforming between the L value and our
value an L value can be used to create
our value in this example I have a L
value I and I can create our value with
I plus 2 and that second example is in
GG X equal to I now what is I is the is
it our value or L value I is obviously
our L value because it has edges and I
address is identifiable however in this
context I is implicitly transformed into
our value so our L value can be
implicitly transformed into our value
however the other way around is not
valid and our value cannot be implicitly
transformed into a l value and our value
should be explicitly used to create our
l value here's an example of using R
value to create our value I have an
integer array V and the V Plus 2 is our
R value
however the dereference of V plus 2 is a
l value which can be assigned with a
different value
instead of continue to talk about what
the our values and our values are let's
talk about what they are not there are
some misconception that needs to be
cleared up miss concept one function or
operator always yields our values this
conclusion can be easily drawn from the
examples of where that we've seen so far
like I equal I plus three is our value
some 3/4 is our value however this
conclusion is not right and here is my
counter example I have a function foo
which returns an integer reference and
in the function I return the global
valuable by reference so the return
value from the function foo is a l value
I can write code foo equal to 15 this
will compile some of you may say well
this is a weird-looking code I never
write code like this well point taken
then how about this example array 3
equal to 15 in this example I'm invoking
operator square bracket on array and
operate a square bracket almost always
generates L value misconcept number 2
our values are modifiable people usually
get this idea from the laksa definition
of our value in C language in C L value
is defined as a value suitable for
left-hand side of assignment
however this definition is no longer
true in C++ because C++ has a Const and
a Const although is a l value it is not
modifiable misconcept number three our
values are not modifiable this seems to
be pretty obvious in our examples I plus
three is our value and it's not
modifiable some three four is our value
and it's not modifiable
however this conclusion is only true for
the built-in types it is not true for
user-defined the type or class for
example I can call the default
constructor of dog to create a dog and
then invoke the function Park on the dog
the function Park could change the state
of the stock so this our value dog is
modifiable a summary if you cannot
remember everything that I've talked
about our value and L value please do
remember the summary number one every
C++ expression yields either our value
or al value number two if an expression
has an identifiable memory address it is
a l value otherwise it's already that's
all for today's session thank you for
watching bye bye