hello everyone today we will talk about
the difference between struct and class
here we have a struct off person T and
it has a name of stream and an age of
unsigned integer and we also has a class
of person and it also has a name of
string and age of unsigned integer now
what's the difference between these two
the difference is for struct it's data
members are public by default and
forecast it's data members are private
by default so this is the only
difference between struct and class as
far as the language is concerned but
usually we'll add another level of
semantic difference between struct and
class struct is used for small passive
objects that carry public data and have
know of few basic member functions you
know in other words a struct is used for
a data container and the class is
usually used for bigger and therefore
more complicated active objects that
carry private data and it interface with
outside would flow public member
functions in other words a class is used
for more complex data structure
but this is just a convention there's
nothing in the language that enforces
you to follow this convention for
example nothing can stop you from giving
the struct
a private data integer height and the
nothing can stop you from giving a class
a public data integer height however
this is a good convention to follow and
you'd better follow it unless you have
some special reason
another convention is a class data
member are usually named with a trailing
underscore and that struck the data
member and named as the same way you
name a regular valuable now in the main
function I create a person t PT and I
can access pts data member directly G G
dot H for example I want to print it out
and then I create a person P and I also
want to print out piece H this will not
compile because H underscore is a
private data of the person if I really
want to access the private data of a
class I have to provide some public
interface for that unsigned H and all
this function does is return the H
underscore and then in the main function
I can call age
and since this function only fetch the
data of the age and that doesn't change
it so we should make this function
constant function and if later on I do
want to change the age then we need to
provide another public function to
change the age
and in the main function we can set the
age to a different value
so this function is usually called Gator
or accessor and this function is usually
called setter or near theta and that
Gator function is almost always a Const
function now some of you may want to
start complaining if we have a private
data member and we defined getter and
setter for this private data member then
what's the point of making this data
member private we could just make it
public and off sudden it saves us the
additional effort of defining these
valid member functions when we create
object-oriented code we want to separate
the interface from the implementation we
want to encapsulate the complicated
implementation and only talk to the
outside world through interfaces and in
the in this case these functions are
interface and these variables are
implementation if you make the data
member public essentially you are
exposing the internal implementation to
the outside world which usually will
bring a lot of headache
in the long run for example if you're
later on decided that H underscore is
not a proprietary ball you want to
change it with setter and getter
function it is very easy to change the
variable name but if the data member is
public and your client has been using it
or all over the place then you have to
change this variable in many different
places
another example is if you want to add
some rules to setting the age for
example a person's age should not be
larger than 200 then with the set
function you can easily
did you check at the beginning of this
function but if the valuable is public
then there's no easy way to enforce that
rule so this is the idea of having
setter and getter function instead of
making the variable public on the other
hand having too many of setter and the
getter function is also not a good
design practice if I have to provide
setter and getter for many of my private
data member it means that my data need
to be used by somebody else if that is
the case why the data belongs to me why
the data not belong to somebody else so
having too many of setter and getter
function indicates there's some problem
with my ID file maybe I should architect
my design models in a different way so
in general you should avoid using too
many of setter and getter function in
your code as a side note some of you
might be curious why we have this weird
convention of trailing underscore for
cos theta member in the very old days
many people use M underscore to denote a
casted data member but then people start
to think why using two character to
denote calculator member if we could
just use one so some people think of
using leading underscore two for that
purpose and actually the leading
underscore is the official naming spin
aiming convention in Python for private
class data member but the problem with
C++ is the leading underscore is already
used for other purpose it is used for
global variables it is used for the
internal implementation related
variables particularly the underscore
followed by a capital letter
and underscore underscore our why delay
used in the internal implementation this
is why people have in vain invented the
trailing underscore notation for the
cast data member but again a convention
is a convention there's nothing right or
wrong here and it is most important for
you to be consistent with the existing
convention that is already used in the
project that you are working on a
summary of what we have talked about
today
number one you struct for passive
objects with public data and they use
class for active objects with private
data
number two use setter and getter
function to access a class's data
instead of making that data public
number three avoid making setter and the
Dec getter function if possible thank
you for watching feel free to subscribe
to my channel and check out the other
videos I have see you next time