hello welcome to C++ advanced today we
are going to talk about a special coding
technique called resource acquisition is
initialization what it basically means
is using objects to manage resources
resources could be memory hardware
device network handle et cetera let's
look at the example I have a mutex mu
and the in function a I block the mutex
and then do a bunch of things and then
unlock mutex this is a pretty regular
looking code but there is a problem with
this code the problem is the statement
of unlocking music mutex may not be
executed because a doing a bunch of
thing could return to function a
prematurely
even if it didn't even if it doesn't
return it may throw an exception and in
either case the mutex will be locked
forever so we need to need a way to
guarantee that the mutex will be
unlocked once it is no longer needed
let's look at how solution the solution
is to use the resource acquisition is
initialization technique here I have a
class lock the class lock have a private
data member which is a pointer to mutex
and in the constructor of the lock
the mutex will be locked and in the
destructor of the lock mutex will be
unlocked now in function a whenever I
want to lock the mutex I construct a
lock and then do whatever things that I
want to do and by the end of function a
my lock will be destroyed from the stack
and then the destructor of the lock will
be invoked so mutex will be unlocked the
conclusion we can take from this example
is the only code that can guaranteed to
be executed after exception is thrown at
the destructor of the objects deciding
on stack so in this example the
destructor of my lock is guaranteed to
be executed so our resource management
needs to be tied to the lifespan of a
souped suitable objects in order to gain
automatic the allocation and reclamation
another good example of resource
acquisition is initialization is shared
pointer a shared pointer is a reference
counting smart pointer it counts a
number of pointer points to itself and
when that number which is 0 the smart
pointer will be destroyed
so in now in function a I created a new
dog and assign the new dog's pointer to
a shared pointer pd-1 speedy goes out of
scope or in other words once there's no
more pointer points to PD and a new dog
will be destroyed let's look at another
example
I have a class dog class trick and a
function chain which change that change
the dog with some kind of dog trick I
have a function get trick which returns
a trick now in the main function I
invoke the chain function with the
parameter dog is created from a new dog
and the parameter dog trick is get from
the cat check function now do you see
any problem with this kind of code let's
examine on what happens in the train
functions primate passing more
specifically is part of the code the
there are three things happening one is
creating a new dog
second thing is invoking the get trick
function and lastly construct a shared
pointer and assign the dog to the shared
pointer now in C++ the order of the
three operations are not fixed it is
compact completely up to the compiler so
if the compiler decide to execute the 3
operation in this order
then there's a problem the gastric
function might throw an exception and if
that happen we have created a new dog
and that a new dog is has not being
assigned to a shared pointer yet so the
memory of the new dog will be leaked
then the conclusion where we can take
from this example is don't combine the
operation of storing objects in a shared
pointer with any other statement in
other words put the storing objects
insured pointer statement to a standard
long statement so in this example we'll
extract this part of the code and then
now now our code is thread-safe because
the new dog once it's going to get
created it will be always assigned to a
shared pointer and there were no longer
the possibility of memory leak
our last note what happens when the
resource management object is copied so
in this example I create our one form
mutex mu and then copy can construct our
two from l1 usually the mutex is
mutually exclusive so it cannot be
called shared by multiple clients so one
solution for the for this is prohibit
copying completely and we can do that by
disallow the copy constructor and copy
assignment operator from being used by
our client and to see how to do that
please watch my another session which is
disallow compiler generated functions
and we're not going to talk about that
in this session solution to sometime the
resource can be shared by multiple
clients and in those kind of scenario or
we need to always want to make sure if
that resource will be released
appropriately once all the clients are
done with it so we need to implement
some kind of reference count mechanism
and to keep track of the number of
clients who is using the resource and we
can do that with the shared pointer in
previous example we have we have seen
that shared pointer can take one
parameter which is a new created object
that's starting on heap
the shared pointer constructor can take
a second parameter which is at the litre
a deleter
is a function that will be invoked when
the shared pointer is destroyed and the
default value for the deleter is the
operator delete so in this example once
the shared pointer PD is delay is
destroyed the operator delete the
default value of the litre will be
performed upon the new dock and a good
thing about the shared pointer is that
the litre can be customized to any
function you like and here we're going
to take advantage of that now let's look
at the new implementation of the lock
class and now it has a private date
member peanut X which is a shared
pointer to a mutex the constructor of
the log initialize the PMU text with the
pointer of the mutex as the first
parameter and the mutex unlock function
at the second parameter the deleter
in the body of the constructor it will
lock the Premio type P lock the mutex so
what this means is when the lock is
created it will lock the mutex and when
there's no more pointer points to P
mutex the mutex will be unlocked
let's look at the example again I create
mute log l14 mutex and then can copy
construct l2 from l1 by this time we
have two pointers points to peameal tags
and the reference count is two and by
the time both l1 and l2 goes out of
scope the number of pointer points to
premio tags will become 0 that means
premio texas deleter will be invoked and
then the period the mutex will be
unlocked so that completes our solution
for our solution 2 which guarantees the
unlocking of mutex once there's no kind
is using the mutex anymore that's all
bye bye