ruthless iterator is a little bit tricky
to use that's why we need to talk about
it there are two ways to declare a
reverse iterator one is using a
temporary class of reverse iterator
another one is using the type of reverse
iterator that's nested inside a
container and they're both doing the
same thing actually one is a type def of
another and here is how to traverse a
vector with reverse iterator first I
define our our ETA which is a reverse
iterator and then I use the continuous
member function our begin and our end so
as a result the content of the vector
will be printed out in a reverse order
reverse iterator and the regular
iterator can be converted from each
other here I have defined a regular
iterator etre and a reverse iterator are
Eater and I can convert a litter into a
reverse iterator and assign it to our
eater however the other way around
won't work I cannot explicitly convert a
auditer back to a litter to do that I
have to use the reverse iterators member
function base so what does the best
function do the C++ standard says best
function will return current iterator
but what does the current iterator mean
the answer might surprise you
here I have a vector of integer that has
one two three four five and then I used
the find function from our begin to our
end to find the item of three and assign
the resulted iterator to a reverse
iterator or ETA then I print out the
content of our eater naturally it will
print out three then I use the base
function to get the are uterus current
iterator and assigned it to eater and
then I print out the content of ETA
guess what will be printed out it will
print out 4 this is what often times
surprised the beginners the reverse
iterator and it'll that can be converted
from each other but they are not
pointing to the same thing how does this
happen
let's look at our picture here I have a
vector and back dot began pointing to
the first item of the vector and vector
and pointing to the one after the last
item of the vector so where is the our
begin on our end or begin pointing to
the last item and our end pointing to
the item before the first item of the
vector
so that is what the current iterate Amin
the current iterator of our end is begin
the current iterate of our begin is end
so they are not pointing to the same
thing they are off by one element and
the same thing for eater and our eater
if our eater is pointing to n then our
it at the base or eater is pointing to n
password they're off by once one item so
the current literature is the reverse
iterator increment by one this is why
our eater point into three and eater is
pointing to for now let's look at more
examples again our eater is pointing to
three and when I insert our eater nine
nine will be inserted before our eater
and since our eater is iterating
backwards so the place before our it is
actually after three between three and
four so nine will be inserted between
three and four if I insert our eater top
base nine nine will be inserted before
our eater third base since our eater
debase is a regular iterator not a
reverse iterator and either the base
point into four so nine will be inserted
before four so now is inserted between
three and four so insert our eater and
insert our database have the same result
however this is not true for Eurasia
again our eta is pointing to three and
if I do back dot erase our eater free
will be removed sold without is one
proof or five however if I do vac dot
erase our it at third base
since our database is pointing to for
four will be removed so the result is
one two three five
so as you see reverse iterator is a
little bit tricky to use and you need to
be careful when use it in case you
haven't noticed I have a or in between
the two insertion and it is very
important for me to have a or in between
the two insertion if I insert our eater
nine and then do insert are at a base
nine what will happen undefined behavior
remember for a vector whenever you
insert something into it or remove
something from it the pointers that
previously pointing to the vectors
content will get invalidated and same
thing for references and iterators it is
very important to keep that in mind and
that the you lace also will invalidate
the pointers and references and
iterators if you want them not to be
invalidated you have to use a list or
associative containers or unordered
containers
that's all for today thank you for
watching feel free to subscribe to my
channel so when I post a new video you
will be updated or you can go to my
channels home page and see what I'm
offering today bye bye