hello everyone last time we've talked
about the chicks of removing elements
from a container for vector and attack
you should use algorithm function remove
followed by mem function in race for
list you should use lists member
function remove and for associative
container and unload at the container
you should use their member function in
race today we will talk about removing
elements and doing something else for
example I have a Mountie set of integer
and I want you to move other ones and
every every time I remove a one I want
to print a message to the stand out
because I want to know it whenever our
element is removed and I cannot do it
with all the functions the LM function
remove the member function remove or the
member member function in race so I will
manually create a loop to do the job and
here's what I am doing I use ETA equal
to C dot begin eternal just equal to a
sedan and E to a plus plus and if the
element of ETA is equal to 1 I call
seated erase ETA and print a message
erase the one item of ETA now you may
want to pause the video and think what
would happen to this code let's run it
it prints out erased one item of one and
then the program crashed so the first
element of one is erased and then the
program crashed or happened in the first
loop of the for loop eta is equal to C
dot begin which is the element of one
since this element is equal to 1 it is
erased successfully and then something
bad happened after the code of seated a
Lay's eater is finished the element that
Hitler was pointing to is erased and
every time an element is erased the
iterator that was pointing to that
element is invalidated so it is
invalidated it is no longer a valid
iterator anymore and this is true for
all containers iterators of erased
elements are always invalidated so when
we go to the second run of the for loop
and check if it equal to C dot end the
result is undefined behavior and in this
case the undefined behavior is the
program crashed so how can we fix this
one way to fix it is we can move the
incrementing of ETA 2 over here now
since this is a post incrementing of ETA
it will return the old iterator for C to
erase and it is advanced to the next
element successfully
and that the since the eater is already
pointing to the next element we need to
move this statement to the before the
race and when we'll go to the second run
of the for loop it is already pointing
to the next element if it is not equal
to one when you need to increment the
eater now let's run that loop on the
program now all the ones are erased
successfully and the program did not
crash so this is how you erase elements
from associative containers with
handcrafted loop now how about the other
containers what about vectors can I use
this same way to erase elements from a
vector let's try it
and run it
as you see only three elements of one
are erased now what happened four-vector
when never an element is erased all the
iterators after that element are
invalidated so whenever one is erased
all the iterators that points to any one
of the rest of element gets invalidated
so even though it is advanced to the
next element successfully it is still a
invalidated iterator so the rest of the
program still has undefined behavior and
in this case the undefined behavior
gives you an illusion that the program
is running okay
which is worse than crashing the correct
way to do it is this get er equal to say
that erase eater because the vectors
erase function always return a valid
iterator that points to the next element
after that you raise the element now
let's run it
now all that ones are erased and the
program did not crash so this is the
correct way to erase elements from
sequence container and unordered
container as a summary for sequence
container an unloaded container you use
the return value from the erase function
as the next element and for associative
container you use post incrementing to
advance to the next element you can't
use the returned value because
associative containers of utilize
function returns nothing now I have to
confess that I have been misleading you
to handcraft your own group of course
you don't have to hand craft your own
loop you can always use the algorithm
now let me show you the library solution
let me remove this loop first out define
a function it's called equal one it
takes one parameter of integer e if e
you cut one it print out a message and
then return true otherwise it will
return false and then I call the
algorithm function will move if remove
if setup begins at the end equal one and
followed by the member function erased
to do the actual work of evasion and
let's run it
as you see this also removed all the
ones from the container so we can
accomplish the same thing without
worrying about all the pitfalls of
handcrafting a loop of elation now you
may say this is not flexible what if I
want to erase 12 do I need to create
another function to check if e equal to
12 that is a good point we can make our
solution better we can add add another
integer parameter called P and if e
equal to P it returns true otherwise it
will return false and in the removi
function we can use find function to
bind the second parameter to any number
we want say we want to remove 12 and run
it only one item of 12 is removed now
some people may say this is still not as
flexible as I wanted it to be because if
I want to print out different message I
still need to create different function
for that alright we can make it even
better and we could use a lambda
function to do the job with lambda
function it is almost as flexible as
handcrafting a loop and without worrying
about all the Saturday of handcrafting a
loop
and also with lambda function or the
code are located in the same place
not like locating in another function
now let's run it and see if it works it
works 12 is removed so as you see I'll
put some plus lambda function is a very
powerful combination as well as you get
used to the syntax of a lambda function
that's all for today thank you for
watching feel free to subscribe to my
channel so when I post a new video you
will be updated or you can go to my
channels home page and see what I'm
offering today bye bye