hello everyone today I'll start using a
live demo kind of presentation to show
you the coding techniques and see how it
works first let me introduce you a
helper function called print it prints
out all the contents of a container and
prefix it with a message of stream and
here I have a vector of int C which
contains a bunch of integers and I print
C and original see what it prints out
and the content of the vector is printed
out successfully so our environment is
good to go today we'll talk about the
removing items from a container let's
see I want to remove all the ones from
the vector C remember in one of the
previous video I mentioned that if there
are same function in a containers member
function and al-sham function you should
prefer using the member function so I
start by searching the vectors member
function see if anything I can use and I
see there's a function called erase
bingo that's what I need so here's what
I'm gonna do
I use a iterator to iterator slew the
members of the container see and if it
equal to one I erase it otherwise I just
increment the eater and to see how it
goes as you see after the loop of erase
all the ones are removed from the
original vector mission complete
although this code can get the job done
this is actually a horrible way of
removing items from a vector when I
remove the first one all the items after
that moved one item toward the front and
then when I remove the second one all
the items after that I once again move
one item toward the front this is a very
inefficient way of removing items if the
size of the vector C is N and the number
of items to be removed is M then the
complexity of this code is n times of M
this is a very inefficient way of
removing item from vector a more
efficient way is actually using
algorithm function removes the algorithm
function remove only moves the Unruh
moved items to walk to the front once
instead of M times so the complexity is
n now let's comment out this four
portion of the code and see how it runs
oops we have a problem here
although the unremoved items are moved
towards the front as we expected the
vector CEO also contains some other
items as I mentioned before algorithm
functions has no idea about the
containers they only know the data
through the iterators
so the algorithm function you move has
no idea whether the data is stored on a
dynamic array or a binary tree or a hash
table that is why it is impossible for
the algorithm function you move to
actually remove the items from the
container so this function you move will
do what it can do which is move all the
unremoved items to the front of the
vector and then return the iterator
which points to the new logical end of
the new vector so to complete the task
of removal we need a pointer is reiter
to save the new end and then call the
member function of the vector arrays to
actually remove the item now let's run
it now the removal walk is truly
finished we have removed all the ones in
vector C and what will be the capacity
of C let's check it out as you see the
capacity of C is still 10 we have
reduced the size of C from 10 to 5 and
the C is still occupying as much memory
as it does before if that piece of
memory is important to you and you want
to release them back to the system there
is one extra step to do
you can call the function shrink to fit
which will release the unused memory
back to the system now let's run it now
the capacity of C is reduced to 5
however this function shrink to fit only
exists in C++ 11 if you are using Otzi
pass pass you can use the swap check and
this should also do the job of shrinking
the memory now let's run it as you see
now the capacity is 5 so the memory is
shrinked now let's talk about new move
elements from a list since we've just
learned a lesson from the backticks
example we'll use the absent function
remove followed by the member function
erase and run it this also gets the job
done for a list but this is not the
optimal way of removing items list has a
member function called remove and the
decimal move function can do the job of
removing items more efficiently why is
that as we mentioned the algorithm
function remove does the job by moving
the Unruh moved items towards the front
of the vector but the member function
remove doesn't do that the member
function you move knows the data
structure of a linked list so it does
still remove by clicking the forward
pointer and the backward pointers which
is more efficient so now this is a
faster easier and cleaner way of
removing items for a list
now let's look at a new move elements
from associative container or unordered
containers we have a multi set of
integer C and we want to remove all the
ones we look at the multi set mem
function and we don't see a dedicated
remove function like the list does so
maybe we should go back to use that will
move algorithm followed by erase
function the answer is no you don't
although multiset doesn't have a
dedicated remove member function it has
a much better version of erase function
the multi sets the erase function can
remove items by value and do it quickly
let's comment out this portion of code
and run it the multi sets erase function
only needs logarithmic time to do the
removal instead of linear time and for
unordered container it is even faster it
only needs amortized constant time to do
the erase so in both case you should use
the member function in race to do the
function of removal a similar way of
removing elements from a container for
vector or tack use out some remove
followed by member function erase for
lists use member function remove for
associative container or unordered
container used member function erase
that's all for today thank you for
watching feel free to subscribe to my
channel so when I post a new video you
will be updated or you can go to my
channels home page and see what I'm
offering today bye bye