last time we have covered in detail how
attack and vector works and today we'll
go back to the original problem that we
were trying to solve which is when we
should use a vector and when we should
use attack the obvious answer is if you
need to push front a lot you should use
a deck because push front is expensive
for vector and if the performance is
important to you you should use vector
because in general vector is faster than
attack these two statements work okay as
a general guideline but they are not
enough there are a lot of things you
need to consider if you don't want to
suffer later on as the data stars become
bigger and bigger first the element type
if the element type is not of a trivial
type or a built-in datatype a deck is
not much less efficient than a vector
that is because the cost of the
construction and the destruction starts
to dominate the performance and that the
performance of the containers themselves
becomes less important number two memory
availability as we said a vector always
requires that data to reside in the
contiguous memory chunk and some time
especially when that vector becomes big
and bigger allocating a large contiguous
memory could become a problem that is
because of either it is an embedded
system and has limited memory size or
the chunk of data simply becomes too big
or the memory is heavily fragmented so
if the allocation of large contiguous
memory could become a problem
you should prefer using deck
number three frequency of unpredictable
growth say we have a vector int back and
we have a for loop 4 into X equal to 0 X
less than 1025 X plus plus and vac dot
pushed back X this will push back 1024
integers into the vector one by one and
during this process 11 reallocation will
be performed assuming the growth ratio
is 2 and as we said reallocation is
expensive the workaround is using
reserve function to minimize the number
of reallocation to be performed however
to do that we have to have some
knowledge of how the vector closed
otherwise the reserve function can't
help much so if the growth of the
container is completely unpredictable
you should prefer using deck because
deck has no reallocation number for
invalidation of pointers references and
iterators because of growth say I have a
backed of int which has four integers in
the vector and I have a integer point of
P which points to back three and then I
call vac dot push back 6 which push
backs another item of 6 into the vector
and then I print out the content that P
was pointing to this results in
undefined behavior
because when I push back six it triggers
reallocation and the reallocation will
invalidates all the pointers that
previously was pointing to the data of
the vector and that pointer could be a
row pointer could be a reference could
be a iterator any one of these will be
invalidated however if I do the same
thing for Dec the result is okay it will
print out five so for that as long as
you are growing the deck at both ends
all the pointers will not be invalidated
but if you insert elements or remove
elements in the middle of the deck the
pointers will also be invalidated so
that does a better job of maintaining
the integrity of the pointers number
five a vector has a unique function
which is it can serve as a portal to see
say we have a C function which can which
takes an integer pointer and size as
parameter for vector we can easily pass
the address of the first element of the
vector and the vector size as parameter
to the C function it is very convenient
the only other container that can do
that is the container array but the
container array is not as easy to use as
a vector for any other containers such
as a list you have to copy all the data
to a vector and then pass the vector
data to the C function
so the important thing to remember is
the edges of the first element of a
vector can be used as a raw array or a
pointer however there's one exception
which is a vector of pool but this
doesn't harm the vectra's unique do they
as a pot o to C because C doesn't have a
pool type anyway say we have a sip
response function which takes a pool
pointer and a size as a parameter
and we have a vector of pool back and we
call the C++ function with the edges of
the first element of vac and that size
this code will not compile because a
vector of pool is optimized so that each
value of the vector is represented by
one bit so the edges of the first
element of the vac is not a bull pointer
so this cannot be passed as a pointer to
the sacred forest function and the work
run is you can use a vector of int or
bit set a summary if push Front is
frequently used prefer tack if the data
type is a beauty in type prefer vector
if the data type is not a beauty in type
prefer tack if allocation of large
contiguous memory is challenging prefer
tack if the data growth is unpredictable
proof.proof attack if it is important to
maintain the pointers integrity prefer
tack
if the data is frequently pastor to a c
function prefer vector that's all for
today thank you for watching feel free
to subscribe to my channel so when I
post a new video you will be updated or
you can go to my channels home page and
see what I'm offering today bye bye