hello everyone today we will talk about
vector and attack which one should be
used vector and the Dec have very
similar interfaces the BIG's the
difference on the interface is a vector
can easily grow on one end and that deck
can easily grow on both ends other than
that they are very similar and because
of their similarity people often have
difficulty deciding which one to use
despite the similar interfaces vector
and the deck are actually very different
data structures and because of that
difference often time you prefer using
one over the other and how to decide
which one to use
that is today's topic first let's look
at an example of vector we have a vector
of int vac which contains 2 3 4 5 and we
know that vector has a member function
called size which indicates how many
items already in the vector and it also
has a mem function called capacity which
indicates how many total items can be
inserted in the vector and let's run it
and see what are these barriers
as you see the VEX size is four and the
VEX capacity is also four which means
all the memories are fully used by the
vector now I want to insert another item
of six into the vector I push back six
and see what's the new size and the
capacity as you see after push back six
the new size is five which makes sense
because now the vector contains five
elements but the new capacity is eight
how did this happen let me show you with
some pictures at first the vector
contains two three four five and both of
excise and capacity are four so all the
spaces are fully occupied now I want to
push back another item of six but the
vector is four there's no room for me to
insert another item or can the vector do
it creates a new array which has twice
the capacity of the original one and
then copy all the data to the new array
now it can easily insert the new item of
six into the new array so now the vector
size is five and in fact s capacity is
eight as you see a vectors capacity
grows exponentially it grows by certain
ratio in this case this ratio is two but
it doesn't have to be to some
implementation use 1.5 as the ratio now
the vector has a new array which
contains all the data remember the new
array is a different away from the old
array so what will happen to the old
array the old array will be simply
deleted and its space will be released
back to the system so this is how a
vector grows and involved this process
of reallocation and from this we can see
some drawbacks of a vector first of all
the expensive reallocation every time a
reallocation happens the original data
will be copied to a new location and
other originals will be destroyed that
is a lot of construction and destruction
and the second delay a vector requires
contiguous memory imagine I already have
ten thousands of data in the vector and
when the reallocation happens I need to
allocate 20,000 data of contiguous
memory that could become a big problem
especially when the memory is already
heavily fragmented so this makes a
vector exception prone when the vector
size is big now let's see some more
examples of vector I have created a
class doc and I have a vector of dog
back which has the size of 6 the result
of this is 6 dogs are created with
default constructor and Feud into the
vector so if we learn this program it
prints out size equal to 6 and capacity
is also 6 now let me create another
example example two I have a vector of
dark back to and since back to is empty
so back to the capacity is zero and
vector size is also zero and then I
resize back to to 6 this has the same
effect as the example 1 in other words 6
dogs are created with default
constructor and the field into the
vector back to so if we run this program
both back and back to has size of 6 and
capacity of 6 now let me create example
we have a vector of dark back three and
we call vac three that reserved six what
will this do
let's first run it as you see back three
size is zero and capacity becomes six so
the reserve function increases the
capacity of the vector and doesn't
increase the size of the vector so no
tox default constructor will be invoked
this provides a very important function
to us
remember the expensive reallocation of a
vector happens only when the capacity of
the vector is four so if we already have
some idea how many items this vector
will be holding we can reserve that
amount of memory for this factor so that
we can avoid the expensive reallocation
altogether and that is the next thing I
want to talk about the strategy of
minimizing reallocation if the next
number of items that the factor will be
using is known you can always use the
function reserve max to reserve that
amount of memory space for the vector so
that it won't incur any overhead of
reallocation however if that max number
of item is not known but you have some
rough idea of when this vector will stop
growing then what we can do is we can
preserve as much memory as we can and
once all the data is inserted Kim of the
rest of the memory that is unused do you
remember how to trim off the unused
memory for vector you could use the
function shrink to fit for say plus 11
for several files or three you could use
the swab check
now let's look at how the deck works
deck looks very similar to a vector but
the underlying implementation is very
different a deck stud weighs a fixed
size array to hold the data and when
this array is full and there is no more
space to push back it allocates another
fixed sized array and similarly if
there's no more space to push front it
also allocates another fixed size array
before that array so this is how attack
grows it grows in both direction and it
closed linearly with a fixed size it
doesn't grow expand exponentially like
the vector does so for tack we have
following observation number one the
deck has no reallocation as the deck
grows in both ends the data of the deck
will never be reallocated because the
capacity is four they stay where they
are so deck has no function of reserve
and the capacity because deck doesn't
need them secondly a deck is generally
considered to be slightly slower than a
vector that is because number one deck
has a more complex data structure and
all that complexity comes in with random
cost
number two since the data of attack is
not sitting in a contiguous memory
memory chunk a deck will suffer from the
problem of locality a deck will incur
more page faults or cache misses than
similarly sized the vector however
modern compiler usually will cast the
data of attack together so that it will
suffer less from the locality problem
that is why our deck is only slightly
slower than a vector that's all for
today
thank you for watching feel free to
subscribe to my channel so when I post a
new video you will be updated or you can
go to my channels home page and see what
I'm offering today bye bye