hello everyone let's start today's
discussion with a question we have
functor LSB less which checks if the
last digit of one integer is less than
the last digit of another integer and
the way the functor of LSB less I
created a set of integer it is called s
and s contains 21 23 26 27 and because
it's a set it is always sorted now I use
the algorithm function find to find the
item of 36 and save the result in
iterator 1 and then I use member
function find to find the item of 36 and
save the result in 82 the question is
which items will eat a while and it to
be pointing to the eater one will be
pointing to as that end this is what we
would expect because 36 doesn't exist in
s and when the arizim find can't find
the item of 36 it will return a iterator
pointing to the end of the container as
the member function find returns an
iterator that's pointing to 26
so the algorithm function and the member
function behaves differently remember in
one of the previous videos that I
mentioned when al-qasim function has the
same name as a containers member
function in general you should prefer
using the member function I said in
general because there are exceptions and
this is one of the exception the
algorithm function and the member
function are not exactly doing the same
thing so which one to use is depending
on what you want to do not just to the
performance consideration anymore now
let's spend some time to find out why
they are behaving differently both the
algorithm find under the member function
find use certain comparison function for
searching the algorithm find uses
operator equal for searching so it
checks if any one item of s is equal to
36 and the things there's none of the
item is equal to 36
the algorithm returns up iterator points
to s done end
the mem function find uses operator less
than for searching it checks if X is not
less than Y and Y is not less than X to
check if an item is found and recall
that s is a set of integer that uses LSB
less as a comparison function so the
less than is defined as LSB less which
checks the last digit of the number only
and if you only look at the last digit
26 is not less than 36 and 36 is not
less than 26 so these two are equivalent
that is why the member function find
returns a iterator pointing to 26 so in
summary the membership member function
find is looking for equivalence and the
algorithm find is looking for equality
note that if I create a set with the
default comparison function instead of
my own comparison function of LSB less
then both the algorithm find and the
member function find will give me the
same result both return iterators
pointing to a stud and
now the question is there are many
algorithm functions and that there are
many member functions how do I know
which one is checking for equivalence
and which one is checking for equality
the safest thing to do is look it up in
the document but there are guidelines
that you can follow if the function is
using operator less than or it's like
for comparison than it is checking for
equivalence typically what that means is
the function is a algorithm that works
with sorted data or the function is a
methyl function of a container that
contains sorted data such as a such
associative container secondly if the
function is using operator equal or it's
a like for comparison then it's checking
for equality and typically what that
means is the function doesn't require
the data to be sorted and here I give
you more example of algorithms that
check for equality search find and find
first of adjacent search and some more
example of algorithms that check for
equivalence binary search includes lower
bound upper bound as you see these are
the algorithms that require the data to
be sorted applying them on unsorted data
results in undefined behavior the
important thing for you to remember
today is whenever you use a function to
search or to remove certain element make
sure you understand the difference
between equality and equivalence and be
aware there might be different versions
of functions for them sometimes they
both will give you the same result and
sometimes they'll give you different
result so choose a correct one for
yourself
that's all for today thank you for
watching feel free to subscribe to my
channel so when I post a new video you
will be updated or you can go to my
channels home page and see what I'm
offering today bye bye