hello everyone today we will talk about
a pitfall in using STL containers
it's called object slicing say we have a
class talk under the dock box I don't
have a name
yellow dock is derived from dog and the
yellow dog does have a name and the
yellow dog can be constructed with the
name and the yellow dog box
my name is M named in the main function
I have a deck of dog D and I create a
yellow dog Y with the name gunner then I
called DDOT push front y so Y will be
saved at the front of the deck D so D 0
is y then I call this 0 dot back I'm
expecting it to print out my name is
gunner and let's run it it actually
print out I don't have a name so what
happened
remember D is a deck of dog so when D
push front why it doesn't actually push
Y into the deck D what it does is it
take Y as a parameter and copy construct
a dog and then push that new constructed
dog into the deck D so what's get pushed
into D is a dot and d0 is a dog this
process is called object slicing what's
being pushed into D is a sliced version
of Y the wise name is slice the web so
this result is not we want when they say
push front Y we actually want to save Y
into the container D so how can we do
that we can make the tag D a deck of
dogs punter instead of dog and then push
front why we push front the edges of Y
and when it bark it use the pointer
version of the park and remember there's
the last step we need to make sure that
bark function is a virtual function and
now let's run it
now it has print out my name is Gunnar
so remember when an object is passed by
value object the slicing might happen
because of the static accost if you
don't want to the slicing to happen make
sure to use passing by reference now
let's consider if we make the Bach
function a non-virtual function and you
see what happen it is still print out I
don't have a name so this is a park
function from the dog so how does this
happen remember D is a deck of dogs
pointer so when D push front a yellow
dogs pointer the static cast still
happens but the trust only happens to
the pointer not the yellow dog itself so
d0 is a tax pointer and it happened to
be pointing to a yellow dog but since
the bark function is not a virtual
function whether d0 is pointing to a dog
or yellow dog doesn't matter at all d0
is a tox pointer it will invoke the dogs
bark function period
object slicing happens in other places
too for example if I have a dog D 2
equal to Y and in this case D 2 is a dog
that is created from Y by slicing some
of its members off and another example
is for I have a function tool which
takes dog G as a parameter and in the
main function I call Y and here again
why is sliced to create a dog and then
passed to function foo that's all for
today feel free to subscribe to my
channel so when I post a new video
you'll be updated or you can go to my
channels home page and see what I'm
offering today bye bye