hello everyone today we will talk about
boost the optional class let's consider
this function get acing data it will get
data from this queue and then you turn
it as a charm so if the queue is not
empty it will return q dot back else it
will return what what should i will
return here whatever I will return here
it will be a valid a charm so I'm unable
to convey the information that the queue
is empty and the Lewton the value is an
invalid value my best bet is return a
null character but again this is a valid
charm so it doesn't convey the
information that the return the value is
invalid so it seems the return value
from this function should not be just a
charm it should be a different type that
includes all the charts plus a value
that indicates invalid value if you have
watched the other video of boost valiant
it since the be tender value should be
boost variant now pointer type chow
so the lieutenant value should be either
a char or something like a null pointer
to indicate a invalid return value this
is why the boost library provide
optional optional is essentially the
same thing but it has a much more
convenient and powerful interface so if
I have a boost optional char okie now
opie is a optional but it is
uninitialized which means no char is
constructed and then I assign a P equal
to a now opie contains a so with
optional we can provide the information
we need for this function if the app is
not initialized it means the value is
not a valid if the app is initialized
the value is valid so we can return a
boost optional char for this get sync
data function and if the queue is not
empty will you turn a optional
that is initialized with the last item
in the queue otherwise we'll just return
a empty optional
now in the main function I can do up
equal to get a sync data and if the app
is not initialized in other words the
app is empty we print out no data is
available else which means the app is
not empty we print out up contains up
dot gap and end line so this is checking
if op is empty or not you can do the
same thing it was if up not equal to
zero and this gate function must be
called only if the OP is not empty if
you call the gate function when app is
empty it will crash
another way of getting the data is
calling a dereference of the OP note
that an optional can be used in a
similar way to a pointer but you should
not get the impression that optional is
modeled as a pointer because it was not
modeled as a pointer and it could be
dangerous if you think it was modeled as
a pointer there is another function
called op dot reset this will be set up
to uninitialized State if you don't like
if-else statement you can use another
function called op dot get value or Z
and in this case if op is initialized it
will return the data contained in up
otherwise it will return a default value
of Z so return Z if op is empty
alternatively you can use the function
get pointer to return a pointer to the
data this will return now if AB is empty
optional can store any kind of data so
if we have a struct of a that contains a
string name an integer value and then we
construct an instance of a then create
optional a up a 0 up a 0 is an optional
of a but it is not initialized and
constructor of a is not called if I
construct option of a with a then a is
copy constructed into up a
and later on we can use up a s name a
value
so here again an optional can be used in
a similar way to a pointer an optional
can also store a pointer boost optional
a pointer up a P address of a and then I
can use the up AP name equal to Bob
optional can also store reference
a reference of a are a and then we can
use up a are nine equal to pub so this
also changed a dot name optionals can
also be used for comparison by using the
bill relational operator boost optional
int I one which is initialized to 1 and
I 2 is initialized to 9
if I 1 is less than I to and we print
out I I 2 is bigger so if both are
initialized both I 1 and I 2 are
initialized this is the equivalent of
comparing that the reference of i1 and
leti reference I 2
otherwise if one of them is
uninitialized that uninitialized one
will always be considered the smallest
so if we have I three then I 3 is
smaller than I 2 and a smaller than I
one that's all for today
feel free to check out the other videos
I have and see you next time