hello everyone this is the first video
on boost library today we will talk
about lexical caste C++ provides many
different ways of converting a data from
string to other types and from other
types to string and here is a list of
the functions that's available the
problem with using these functions is
there are too many functions for people
who has a short memory like me who can
never remember the last one or two
characters every time I want to use them
I have to look them up in the document
besides the function names are not
uniformed some of them are a to
something and some of them are screen to
something and what's even worse is if I
want to do the reverse operation I want
to convert data from other type to
string I have to use a completely
different method I need to create a
string stream and then left shifter the
data into the stream and then call its
member function to get the final stream
this method of using stream stream is
very powerful if I want to have fine
control over the formatting then using
string stream is still the way to go
however if all I want to do is
converting an integer value into a text
format then using stream stream is both
inconvenient and inefficient it is like
to cure a fly with a cannon of course I
can still use the Odyssey function of s
printf
and as scanf but these functions are
also not convenient to use and they are
not safe
another option is to use function like I
- a but that is non-standard function
this is why boost provide the lexical
cast library which is a safe convenient
and efficient way of do the conversion
from and to a text format so let me give
you a demo of using lexical cast first
you need to include the header file of
next cast and then in the main function
I can induce in HS equal to 23 and the
string a string equal to lexical cast
string s this will convert s from an
integer to a string I can also use that
to form a message string equal to
message plus lexical cast string
a character A+ equal plus lexical cast
school 34.5 a float so as you see I only
need to use the same function name
lexical cast to do a different type of
conversion so this is very convenient
and I not only can convert that data to
a string I can also convert a data to a
ray of character 64
turn a three
I
so this will convert the integer 23 to a
relay of chars now I will do it the
other way around
I'll convert a string to an integer as
equal to I still use the same function
lexical cast int instead of string and I
pass a string to this function this will
convert this string to the integer s and
if I do as equal to lexical cast moon
56.7 8 this is the invalid cast because
56.7 8 is not an integer so this will
flow exception of bad luck circle cast
you can catch it with a child catch
block
and print the message out
and now if I run the program
it prints out exception cut bad lexical
cast source type value could not be
interpreted as target and if I do as
equal lexical
cast int Y you and again this is a bad
lexical cast however if I do the same
function with an additional parameter
for this will tell the lexical cast
function to only pass the first four
character of the string so this is not a
bad cast so this is how to use a lexical
cast it is convenient because all you
need to remember is one name and it is
safe it generates exception and it's
fast it is generally faster than any one
of the methods listed below that's all
for today feel free to check out the
other videos I have and see you next
time