hello everyone today we will talk about
the class in boost called ne ne is the
type of data that can be used to store
any type of data so in the main function
if I create boost any X Y Z and X equal
to string hello then X is storing a
stream then X equal to 2 point 3 and
suddenly X becomes a double y equal to a
Z and Y is starting a char Z equal to
vector int and Z is storing a vector so
ne is kind of similar to variant in
terms of the purpose but ne is more
flexible it can be used to store any
kind of data and variant can only be
used to store a limited number of types
of data but the flexibility is not free
any uses dynamic storage and variant
uses stack based storage so variant is
more efficient in terms of memory
management now I want to print the value
of y Z out Y and line this will not
compile because the left shift operator
is not overloaded for any in order to
print wise value I have to do boost any
cost
ciao why the function any cost will
return a copy of wise data which is Z so
the any cost function is similar to the
gate function for valiant the difference
is any construction returns a copy of
the data and the CAD function returns a
reference of the data and I can also
print the excess value and X is a double
X and the tail returns X's theta which
is 2.3 and if I want to print x value by
the I specify X as int and this will not
work it will slow an exception of bad
any cost and if I any cost X into float
this will still flow the bed any cost
so the type has to be matched exactly
now I want to use Z boost any cost
vector eat
z pushback 23 and then I do int I equals
mu Steny cast vector int Z dot top not
top back now guess what will happen this
will crash because the any cost function
returns a copy of the vector stored in Z
so when I push back 23 I'm pushing back
23 into a copy of the vector so the
vector in Z was still empty when I call
the back function and you can also be
used to store a pointer so say I have an
integer I and boost any P equal to the
edges of I and then later on I can do
integer pointer P int equal to a boost
all cast integer pointer key
so this time anycast returns a pointer
and if I create a vector of any called M
I can do m dot push back to an integer m
dot push back a a character m dot push
back P which is another any of integer
pointer m dot push back boost any this
is a empty any as a placeholder and I
can also create a struct property which
contains a string called name and an any
called value so this is a name value
pair where the value can be actually
data type and if I create a vector of
property called properties then I can
use this variable to store any number of
properties where the value can be
arbitrary data type so this is a very
powerful data structure
we have mentioned in previous video that
a variant can never be empty but a nanny
can be empty so we can check if X is
empty then we print out X is empty one
problem with any is the data type can
only check at run time
unlike variant where you can use visitor
to check the data type at compile time
so if I want to check the type of the
data stored in any I have to use run
time type identification type equal to
type ID char then print out X is a charm
that's all for today feel free to check
out the other videos I have and see you
next time