hello everyone today we will talk about
another boost class variant as we know
in C as well as C++ we have Union so if
I create a union into I float F you then
the same storage space of you can be
used to either store an integer or a
float but not both at the same time so
if I do you I equal to 34 and then you
dot F equal to two point three then you
dot I at this point is over written so
this is how Union works but the problem
with Union is it has to work with plain
old data if I create a union of integer
and a stream then this will not compile
this makes Union or mostly useless once
we enter C++ because in C++ we almost
always deal with classes this is why
boost library provide variant library a
variant is like a union for signals pass
after I included the variant header I
can start user variant boost variant int
stream u 1 and u 2 so u 1 u 2 can be
used to store either an integer or a
string but not both at the fun time you
want equal to 2 u 2 equal equal to
hello so u1 is starting an integer and
the u2 is starting a stream and if I
want to print out to u1 u2 I can simply
do u 1 u 2 and if I run the program it
prints out to and hello now I want to
change u 1 equal to u 1 times of two
this will not compile because the
operator star is not overloaded for
variant so instead we need to do this
get int u 1 and then times of 2 so the
gate function will get an integer out of
you one but you need to be careful not
to make a mistake with this type say I
want to create a string as T equal to
boost get string u 1 this will slow
exception of bad cat because what's
stored in u 1 is really an integer not a
string but later on I can change the
data in your 1 to a different the type
you want equal to good and now you want
becomes a stream and I do you one equal
to 32 and you one becomes a int again so
at different point of time you one can
contain different type of data a variant
can never be empty so if we create a
variant of you three and then you three
will be constructed with the first type
in the type list which is the integer so
if we print out you three and we need to
comment out this bad get and run the
program and you three contains zero so
far we have been using gate function to
fetch the data stored in a variant the
problem with gate function is we have to
know the data type of the data stored in
the valiant and sometimes we don't know
that for example we have a function or
the double which takes a boost variant
int string B
then how do I know what data the V is
storing we don't know it depends on the
person who is calling this function so
we need a better way to fetch the data
stored in a variant and we do have a
better way to do that we can use visitor
here I create a class double visitor
which is a functor and it is derived
from the static visitor class in boost
this functor can take two kinds of
parameters integer or string and it will
do different things based on the type of
the parameter and then we can use the
visitor to operate on the variant u1
equal to two it's an integer boost apply
visitor double visitor u1 as a lose out
u 1 becomes 4 and if we do u2 equal to
hello and we do the same thing boost a
private double visitor u 2 & u 2 becomes
hello hello so in a sense the visitor is
like polymorphism on Valiant
so as you see using a visitor is both
flexible and safe and now i can do even
more powerful things i create a vector
of variant
in swing back and we can do back but
push back good this is a string and back
up push back 23 by integer back now push
back bad another stream and later all I
can create a double visitor F and then
for Auto ex back boost apply visitor F X
so this will apply the double visitor on
each valiant in the vector and do
different things based on the data type
of the valiant that's all for today feel
free to check out the other videos I
have and see you next time